Now, the E Street Band has come
thousands of miles tonight.
And we're here for one reason.
Because you're here.
And where we want to go, we
can't get there by ourselves.
Where we want to go, we can't
get there by ourselves.
We need you.
So I got one question
that I want to ask you.
Can you feel the spirit?
If you can feel the spirit, I want you
to answer me with a "Yeah, yeah!"
Can you feel the spirit?
Yeah! Yeah!
Can you feel the spirit now?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
My three words for Bruce Springsteen
are hope, heart and perspective.
Intense, passionate
and earnest.
Bruce is power.
Bruce is belief.
Bruce is togetherness.
My first experience with Bruce
Springsteen was in here
in this venue, 1987, The
Tunnel Of Love Express Tour.
And my journey
started on that night.
I was nine years old and I was
hanging in the fences up here
and having a blast
and, you know,
there must have been 100 people
behind me who couldn't see the show.
But I was a kid at the time,
so they probably thought,
"Hey, let the boy
enjoy himself. "
But I remember
I recorded the entire show,
three and a half hours,
on an old Walkman,
and on the old cassette tapes,
and I still have them at home.
I keep them in a box and...
Once every now and then,
I stumble on to this box
and I look at it and I smile, you
know, because I actually remember.
I remember the night. It was
a beautiful summer night.
What these tapes represent
is basically why I keep them
and they represent a great day
in a nine-year-old boy's life
and that's priceless.
My favorite singer
is Bruce Springsteen
because I think
he puts like when
he has a concert,
he puts a lot of effort
into his singing.
Like he takes a deep
breath before every song
and like when the
camera goes close up,
you can just see
his veins popping out
because he's working so
hard and after one song
he's as sweaty as
a normal singer would be
after he's done like 10 songs.
These are some of
the pictures that I've...
I won, or I bought
or framed them.
But this particular one,
it's a little moldy.
I used to hold this
picture up to my son
and say, "Daddy, Daddy. "
So I think maybe I played
some head games with my son
for the first few years of his life
thinking that this was his daddy.
A song about growing up.
♪ Well, I stood
stone-like at midnight
♪ Suspended in my masquerae
♪ And I combed my hair
it looked just right
♪ And commanded
the night brigade
♪ I was open to pain
and crossed by the rain
♪ And I walked on
my crooked crutch
♪ I strolled all alone
through a fallout zone
♪ And came out with
my soul untouched
♪ I hid in the clouded
wrath of the crowd
♪ When they said sit down
I stood up
♪ Growing up
♪ Well, the flag of piracy
blew from my mast
♪ My sails were
set wing to wing
♪ I had a jukebox graduate
for first mate
♪ She couldn't sail
but she sure could sing
♪ I pushed B-52 and bombed
them with the blues
♪ With my gear set
stubborn on standing
♪ I broke all the rules,
strafed my old high scho,
♪ And never once
gave thought to landing
♪ I hid in the clouded
wrath of the crowd
♪ But when they said come don
I threw up
♪ Growing up
Hi. I'm Theresa Martin
and this is what I've
collected over the years.
I have an abundance
of love for Bruce.
So, Theresa, when did you actually
become a Bruce Springsteen fan?
I became a Bruce Springsteen
fan in 1982.
Really? And do you recall how
many live shows you actually attended?
I'm not sure. I'm in
double digits clearly.
But I'd say 30 plus.
30 plus, that's quite
an adventure you had.
I also understand that you've won
a few Bruce Springsteen contests.
Is that correct? That is correct.
I've won two.
One being... The first
contest I won was...
Help me.
The Today Show.
That's one. And you know what?
I'm good.
Because you know what?
It was The Today Show.
It was in 2002 when
The Risifirst came out
and I gave birth
to my first son.
And he was a month old.
And I actually was home
and The Today Show
had questions.
I answered them and I won and
we went to New York City.
So I'd kind of like to
introduce my son Dominic.
And this is my son now.
He's 10 years old and...
Well, Dominic, you had a little
bit of a special moment, didn't you?
What's the question?
You had a bit of a special Bruce
Springsteen moment, didn't you?
Yes, I did. And can you
explain that to us?
I've got it.
This is the picture
I got after the concert.
We were waiting on the curb
and a friend was going
to get the vehicle.
And the police came and stopped all
the cars from where they were going.
And a black SUV came.
And in the back seat with his
window down was Bruce Springsteen.
Everyone ran up to the car.
She was told to back off by the
policeman standing next to her.
And I shook his hand while
getting this close-up picture.
Dominic,
where was that concert at?
Fenway Park in Boston.
Awesome. Awesome.
So now you're the next generation
Bruce Springsteen fan.
Yes, I am.
Excellent.
What's your favorite
Bruce song?
Death To My Hometown.
Why?
I like it.
Which is good. However...
Because of the words.
Taught to me by
this person right here.
And when Mommy tells you
to listen to the words,
or understand the words,
what do you say?
Okay.
And do you hear the words?
Yes.
Do you really hear the words?
Okay, I just want to make sure.
Thank you, goodbye.
Thank you, Dominic.
Yeah!
So we got to the
park at four o'clock
with our signs with us,
our home-made signs.
♪ You can't start a fire
I had my "I'll be your
Courtney Cox" sign.
♪ I'm stranded with
a broken heart
I had my Aviator sunglasses on.
It was pouring with rain.
I had my
Courtney Cox T-shirt on.
♪ You can't start a fire
Then James said to me, "Rachel, come on.
Get on my shoulders. "
And I was like,
"Oh, no, I don't want to. "
I felt bad for the people behind us.
They wouldn't be able to see.
He's like, "Come on. You never know
when we're going to see Bruce again. "
Literally, a couple of
seconds into the song,
Bruce spotted me
and started laughing
and he was pointing at me
and I was waving at him.
Next thing I know, I get put on
the big screen with my sign.
The next thing I know, the girl in
front of me just turned around to me
and screamed, "He wants you on the stage!
"He wants you on the stage!"
♪ Hey, baby!
The next thing I know, I'm just being
pushed through a sea of black bodies.
I had my sunglasses on.
I couldn't see anything.
The next thing I know I'm dancing
with Bruce Springsteen on stage.
Before I knew it, it was all over.
That was it.
We took a bow
and he gave me a big hug
and the only thing I could say
to him was, "Bruce, I love you. "
♪ You can't start a fire
♪ Even if we're just
dancing in the dark ♪
♪ I got a '69 Chevy with a 396
I can't get through a day
without listening to Bruce.
His storytelling is perfect.
It's helped me through
serious highs and...
Since then he was two things
for me, a friend and a teacher.
I think most of all he taught me
how to be a man and a decent man
through his songs
and through his life.
Because I lost my
virginity tThunder Road.
Whenever I'm feeling
lonely, or depressed,
I can always listen to oe
of his songs or albums
and it always
helps me feel bett.
A song by Bruce can
stop me dead in my tracks,
even a song I've heard over
and over again for 28 years.
But Bruce
is timeless.
He's helped me live in my own
time and become who I am.
I've been a fan of
Springsteen's all my life.
He was just standing in that
spotlight and he was so powerful
and the whole crowd was just
mesmerised by what he could do
and the stories that he could tell
and I just remember thinking,
"What is this? Who can do this?
What kind of power is that"
♪ And we cover
all the northeast state
♪ When the strip shuts dn
we run 'em in the street
♪ From the fire roads
to the interstate ♪
Hi. My name is Kitty.
I'm a truck driver.
And Bruce Springsteen is my favorite
artist to listen to on the road.
Recently I drove
through Arizona
and I listened to
his album Nebraska
and the song
Atlantic City came on.
And it just felt really good,
listening to that loud,
while driving
through the desert.
In fact, I think every
important moment of my life
has a theme song
that's Bruce Springsteen.
So all of these CDs in my car,
absolutely every single one
is Bruce Springsteen.
Wait, actually one is his wife
Patti, my favorite album from Patti.
But that's all
we listen to in this car,
so my three sons,
they have no choice.
I only listen to Bruce
and they are schooled in the
music of Bruce Springsteen
when they drive
around with Mommy
and I have to take them
all over God's creation.
They know they don't have a choice.
It's no Disney bop nonsense music.
It's Bruce Springsteen.
And I love it, because
it gives me such joy.
I'm so proud of them when they can
sing songs that are 30 years old
from when I was little.
♪ I go driving deep into
the light, in Candy's eyes
♪ She says,
Baby if you wanna be wild
♪ You got a lot to learn
♪ Close your eyes
Let them melt, let them e
♪ Let them burn
'Cause in the darkness
♪ There'll be hidden
worlds that shine
♪ When I hold Candy close
♪ She makes the
hidden worlds mine ♪
Bruce... Bruce's sound
and E Street Band
sounded completely different than
anything else I'd ever heard.
With Clarence in there
and the keyboard layers
and the heavier drumming.
It's like a punchy
soul band or something.
Sexy sax.
Hence began my love
for rhythm and blues
and sex music,
I guess, soul music.
Bruce's lyrics...
...always made me feel...
...like I was going through
someone's family photo album
and looking at their life
and feeling what they felt
and smelling their coffee
and feeling their sadness
and their triumph.
♪ There's a place right on
the edge of town, sir
♪ Rising above
the factories and the fis
♪ Where ever since
I was a child I can remer
♪ That mansion on the hil
♪ In the day you could se
the children playing
♪ On the road that leads to
those gates of hardened steel
♪ Steel gates that
completely surround sir
♪ That mansion on the hill
♪ At night my daddy'd takee
and we'd ride
♪ Through the streets of
a town so silent and still
♪ We'd park on a back rod
down by the highway side
♪ Sit and look up at
the mansion on the hil♪
So, David, what does
Bruce Springsteen mean to you?
Bruce Springsteen means love,
not for him, but for you.
You being a fan, I've had
Bruce Springsteen songs
rammed down my throat 24/7.
It tends to lose its edge.
It really does.
I've been all over Europe.
So how many concerts
have you been to?
You... I think you reminded me.
It was about eight.
Eight that
I've actually been to.
Yeah, Amsterdam, Paris, I mean,
I've seen some beautiful cities
along the way, but then I've
always had this little bit
where I've had to go to a
concert in the middle of it,
which tends to spoil it for me.
And his dream was to get
on stage with Springsteen.
I heard him talking about
it from the time we met
until it actually happened.
That's my lifelong dream. And I said,
"You're really going to do it?"
And he goes. "I'm going to do
it. " I said, "Do you promise?"
And he said, "I promise. "
So he puts a suit on. He's dragging
me across the street to get there
and as soon as he got up there,
people are going, "Hey, Elvis. "
And they're high fiving him and
they're wanting their picture taken
and they're asking him to sing
songs and he just kind of...
All the anxiety
just melted away.
We had a sign that said... Can
the King sing with the Boss?
Can the King
sing with the Boss?
Bruce started
doing All Shook up.
A one, two...
A one, two, three.
♪ Well, I bless my soul
What's wrong with me?
♪ I'm itching like a mn
on a fuzzy tree
♪ My friends say I'm acting
Wild as a bug
♪ I'm in love I'm all shook up
♪ Hey, hey, hey
All of a sudden he stopped singing
and the band kept playing
and he said,
"Okay, King, come on up. "
And it was like, "Oh, my God, I
can't believe it's happening. "
It was like
my dream of 20 years.
And there I was and I'm
being helped up on stage.
Come on, King!
When I saw him
being pulled up on stage,
everybody around me is like,
"Hey, he's up there. "
Because they all were sharing
the experience with me.
It was surreal. It was like, "Oh,
my gosh, I'm married to Elvis"
"and he's singing with Springsteen
and his dream's realized. "
My heart was just pounding.
I was so excited.
♪ Hey, hey
♪ Well, I bless my soul
What's wrong with me?
♪ I'm acting like a man
on a fuzzy tree
♪ Who do you thank
when you have such luck?
♪ I'm in love, I'm all shook up
♪ Hey, yeah
Right when he was about
to start singing,
his son texted me and said, "Did
my dad get on stage? Ha-ha!"
And I went,
"He's up there now. "
♪ My hands are shaky
and my knees are weak
♪ I can't seem to stand
on my own two feet
I was so happy. I really was.
I grabbed my buddy.
I said, "He's singing
with Bruce Springsteen. "
"He's singing
with the Boss. "
He had the faith
and he handed me the mic
and I said,
"Okay, this is it. "
So I did my best
and as I was singing,
at one point,
I dropped to my knees...
♪ Who do you thank
when you have such luck?
♪ I'm all shook up
♪ Hey, hey, yeah
Take it, Bruce!
And I kick out my leg, which
when you look at the video,
it looks like an Elvis move,
but the fact of the matter is
when I dropped to my knees,
I pulled my hamstring.
I immediately kicked out my leg,
because I'd pulled my hamstring
and then I stood up and my
leg was hurting a little bit
and at that point that's
when I said, "Hit it, Bruce. "
And he did his guitar solo.
And then I realized
that during the guitar solo
that there is no guitar
solo in All Shook Up
and didn't quite know
what to do at that moment
and I turned around
and looked at Max
and I backed up, thinking that I'm
going to have to change the song.
And out of no disrespect to Bruce
or the band, but I backed up
and looked at Max and right at
the end of the guitar solo,
I went into Blue Suede Shoes and
the band was right there with me.
♪ Well, it's one for the mony
Two for the show
♪ Three to get ready Now
go guys go But don't you ♪
And I remember in the corner of
my eye, I see Bruce coming up
and I remember, as I'm
singing, saying to myself,
"Uh-oh, I think you're done, Nick,"
because just by looking at Bruce
and I said, "Okay, Bruce, take
it home. " And he grabs the mic.
Take it home, Bruce!
Elvis has left the building!
Thank you, King.
And then I remember
jumping off the stage and...
He got totally mobbed by the crowd
because they were all so excited.
Everybody wanted to hug him and,
you know, like high five him
and I'm just waiting, because I
just can't wait to like hug him
and kiss him and say, "Oh, my
God, we've realized your dream. "
And it was like a scene from...
Wasn't it like a scene from Rocky and
Adrian were yelling for each other
just to try to catch up to
each other so we can embrace?
And once we did,
it was like the most...
I don't know. The tears fill your
eyes, because you're so happy.
And as we turn around, we look up and
Bruce was holding that last note.
He pointed to us
and he kept saying,
"The Philly Elvis.
The Philly Elvis. "
The Philly Elvis!
Then the last thing he said, which I'll
never forget. He looks and says...
I have no idea where the
he came from.
Thank you, King.
He means inspiration.
He means joy.
And he means salt of the earth.
I know it's three words,
of the three words
but I don't want to alter
salt of the earth.
He's just the best.
He's the best.
Happy, handsome and hot.
Supernatural,
divine, inspiration.
My soul brother.
A local legend.
In three words, I would
say, in him we trust.
Am I looking okay? Okay.
Passion, passion, passion.
It was March 29th, 1976,
right smack in the
middle of the '70s.
And it seemed like
all our parents were gone.
Just working,
busy, drunk
at the country club.
So somehow it was okay
for a group of girls
to go to see a rock 'n' roll
concert on a Monday night
in March of our 9th grade year.
I don't remember what happened
when we got to the concert.
I don't know what happened
to the other girls,
but I know that
as soon as I got there,
as soon as the lights went out,
I made my way
to the front of the stage,
back when you could do that.
And was front and center up against
the stage right in front of Bruce.
Even after all these years and
all the shows that I've seen,
the concert still
defies description.
And I think that only the people
who saw him in the early days
in the small venues,
before the mega crowds...
And when you could get so close
that you were sharing the sweat
and spit of whatever band
member you were closest to,
can really know the ferocity and
intimacy of those concerts.
♪ The screen door sls
Mary's dress sways
♪ Like a vision she dancs
across the porch
♪ As the radio plas
♪ Roy Orbison singg
for the lonely
♪ Hey that's me
and I want you oy
♪ Don't turn me home again
♪ I just can't face
myself alone again
♪ Don't you run back inside
♪ You know just
what I'm here for
♪ You're scared and you're thinking
that maybe we aint that young anymore
♪ Well, show a little fah
There's magic in the nigt
♪ Aln't a beauty but what...
♪ Oh, yeah,
that's all right with me
♪ Good times as long
as I study your pains
♪ Makes crosses from your
lovers Throw roses in the rain
♪ Waste your summer
praying in vain
♪ For a savior to
rise from these streets
♪ Well, I'm no hero
that's understood
♪ Well, all the redemption I can offer,
girl, is beneath this dirty hood
♪ With a chance to
make it good somehow
♪ Hey, what else can we do now?
♪ Except roll down your window
♪ And let the wind
blow back your hair
♪ Well, the night's busted open
♪ These two lanes wil
take us anywhere
♪ We got one last chane
to make it real
♪ To trade in them ws
on some wheels
♪ Climb in back, heaven's
waiting down on the tracks
♪ Well, oh,
come and take my hand
♪ We're riding out tonight
to chase the promised land
♪ Oh, oh, thunder road
Oh, thunder road
♪ Oh, thunder road
♪ Lying out there
like a killer in the sun
♪ Hey, I know it's late but
we can make it if we run
♪ Oh, thunder road, sit tight
♪ Take hold, thunder roa
After graduation, I
couldn't really get a job
and so I started
working at Jamba Juice
making oatmeal
in the early morning.
I'd have to get up
at three o'clock.
I didn't have a car,
so I rode my bike to work
and that was when
Working on a Dreacame out.
I would listen to that on my
way to work and feel like,
"Oh, I'm such
a hard-working person. "
"I'm the backbone of
America. " That's what...
Well, sometimes I feel like that
when I listen to Bruce like,
you know, like I'm really
important, the work I do, the...
The more physically
demanding my job is,
the more important I am,
when I listen to Bruce.
I don't know if that makes any
sense, but that's how I feel.
Madison Square Garden,
2000, the Reunion Tour.
I'd worked in
a factory for 20 years
and I'd saved up
enough money eventually
to afford to go on a Bruce
trip as we call it,
four days in New York, two
concerts at Madison Square Garden.
So me and my lovely wife Kath
stayed in the Hotel Pennsylvania,
across the road from
Madison Square Garden.
We went down to the bar
to pick up our tickets
on the night of the
concert, the first concert,
and excitedly opened the
envelope, looked at the tickets,
looked at the map seating plan
and we were right at the
back, right at the top.
So a bit disappointed,
but we were in New York,
America for the first time.
So looked at the positives,
we went across the road,
up the escalators right to
the top, right to the back,
and as we got to the top level,
this rather bear-like character
in baggy shorts and a beard,
as he walked past me,
muttered the immortal words,
"You want to be upgraded?"
Sorry? Didn't know what he meant?
Didn't quite hear him.
"Let me see your tickets," he said,
so I showed him our tickets.
He looked at them and said,
"I think we can do better than that.
Give me your wrist. "
I put my wrist out and he
slapped an orange wristband
on my wrist and Kath's and
I said, "What's that for?"
He said, "Don't remove that from your wrist.
Don't leave the building. "
"If you leave the building,
you won't be allowed back in. "
And like he'd
said it 1,000 times.
He put our tickets
in his pockets
and then he peeled off a couple
of tickets, gave them to us
and said something like,
"I work for Bruce. I don't
want any money from you. "
"I don't want any recognition. Please
don't point me out to other people. "
"Thank you for your support.
Enjoy the show. "
And he was gone.
So we're looking at the tickets,
entrance whatever it was.
We thought, "We'd better
find this entrance, then. "
So we walked round Madison
Square Garden at the top
and there was no entrance
and I thought,
"I've just given my tickets
to a complete stranger"
"and we've got tickets that
don't get us in anywhere. "
Kath, my wife, pointed out that
we'd just gone past a cocktail bar,
like they do in America, not a
beer stand like in England.
And she said, "There's a couple in
there with orange wristbands on. "
"Let's go and ask them. "
We went to the cocktail bar.
Sure enough, very elegant
couple sitting there,
and we said, "Excuse me".
And we told them our story.
He said,
"Let me see your tickets. "
He looked at the
tickets and he goes,
"You got the best seats in the house.
What's your problem?"
I still found it
a bit hard to believe.
But sure enough we went to
a staff member, showed him
and he just pointed us down
through that entrance
and then the next level down,
keep going, keep going.
We got to the back
of the front section
with the maroon rope
across and thought,
"Oh, we must be behind here somewhere.
This is fantastic. "
We showed the man.
He unclipped the rope.
"Down to the front, sir. "
And we ended up on the front
row at Madison Square Garden
to see Bruce Springsteen
and the E Street Band
in the year 2000.
I got so excited
I bought my wife
three glasses of champagne
at seven dollars a glass.
And I was a factory
worker at the time.
And it was phenomenal.
So that's what it's like to
be a Bruce Springsteen fan.
♪ Early in the morning
factory whistle blows
♪ Man rises from bed
and puts on his clothes
♪ Man takes his lunch,
walks out in the morning ligt
♪ It's the working, the
working, just the working life
♪ Through the mansions of fear
♪ Through the mansions of pain
♪ I see my daddy walking through
them factory gates in the rain
♪ Factory takes his hear,
factory gives him life
♪ The working, the worki,
just the working life
♪ End of the day,
factory whistle cries
♪ Men walk through these gats
with death in their eyes
♪ And you just
better believe, y
♪ Somebody's gonna
get hurt tonight
♪ It's the worki, the working,
just the working life
♪ It's the working, the working,
just the working life ♪
Here we are just hanging out in the
evening at home in our living room,
talking about Bruce Springsteen,
like we do every night.
Yes, we do.
Okay.
Anyway, this is my vintage shirt.
Remember this one?
I hardly ever wear it, because
I have to preserve it.
And I never even went to a show.
How did you get that shirt?
I never even went to a show.
We'd never been able to get
tickets when we had money
and then we didn't have
money, so we couldn't go.
Unfortunately not, but we're
still huge Bruce fans.
Oh, God, honey.
What? We are.
I know we are.
All right, so?
Anyway, yes, this was my ex-boyfriend
who I was living with in Manhattan
and he was a musician and I was
a writer-actress-waitress.
And I think he went to the show,
but I was already seeing you.
Then he was trying to woo me
back with the Bruce shirt.
And it didn't quite work.
And I won.
He might have been able to woo me
back if he'd bought Bruce with him.
Anyway, yeah, so it's
my favorite shirt.
I don't wear it too often.
I don't want to wear it out.
Right, but for this occasion...
But it's funny because we
were talking the other night.
We were saying about how...
You know, we were talking about like
how Bruce is kind of in our lives
and stuff like that and...
And we were talking about
like the fact that we're...
It sounds so stupid, but we
are kind of like the people
that are in his songs
in different ways.
Very much so, blue collar.
Blue collar.
Together 28 years.
Struggling.
Yeah, struggling with the kids
and you go to work
every day in Manhattan
and works with his hands and has
been doing that for over 30 years.
But we're still together.
That's the main thing.
But if you say it one more
time, we might not be.
So I've got these tickets to see
Bruce with my girlfriend in Hamilton
and she calls me on October 20th,
the night before the concert,
while I'm at work and just
tells me, "It's over. "
And I think, "This is going to
be the worst day of my life. "
So I get home, I get drinking and
I don't know what else to do,
or what to think except I
guess I need somebody else
to go see
Bruce Springsteen with me.
And I guess that
won't be too hard to find.
And then I think, "I've got
tickets on the floor. "
And I realized, "No, no, no,
what I need is a sign. "
Hi, Bruce,
I just got dumped.
We all know what that's like.
Where's my man, right there?
What happened, bro?
She didn't think I was
spending enough time with her.
You probably weren't.
Can you get a hug?
Come on up here.
It's going to be okay.
It's going to be all right.
Don't worry about a thing.
I got dumped
plenty of times myself.
Oh, they're regretting it now.
That's right.
She'll be regretting it.
That's right. They left too
soon, man, too soon they quit.
Aha!
And missed that record company
advance money, they left too soon.
♪ We sit in the car
outside your house
♪ I can feel the ht
coming round
♪ I go put my arm around yu
♪ You give me a look
like I'm way out of bounds
♪ Well, you let out one
of your bored sighs
♪ But baby when I lok
into your eyes
♪ I'm going down,
down, down, down
♪ I'm going down, down, down
♪ We get dressed up and we go
♪ Out, baby, for the night
♪ We come home early burning
♪ Burning in some fire fight
♪ I'm sick and tired
of you setting me up
♪ Setting me up just to
knock-a-knock-a-knock-a e
♪ Down, down, down
♪ I'm going down,
down, down, down
♪ I'm going down, down, down
♪ I'm going down
Take me! ♪
All right, my three words are
poet,
comfort,
and gluteus maximostus.
Hope, insurance and redemption.
Working-class hero.
And I think that in general Polish
people could relate to his music,
especially during communism, because
he was singing about freedom.
When you... At the time people
couldn't speak English so well,
so when like in the song
Born in the USA,
they could understand
only the chorus,
so everybody was thinking that,
"Oh, he's praising the fact that
he's an American. It's so great"
I guess that if you hear him singing
Born in the USA with such charisma,
you want to be like that.
I want to be an American, too.
So those were like the sounds of
freedom, I would say, really.
♪ Born down in
a dead man's town
♪ The first kick I took
was when I hit the ground
♪ You end up like a dog
that's been beat too much
♪ Till you spend half your
life just covering up
♪ Born in the USA
♪ I was born in the USA
♪ Got in a little hometown jam
♪ So they put a rifle
in my hand
♪ Sent me off to a foreign land
♪ To go and kill the yellow man
♪ Born in the USA
♪ I was born in the USA
And a special moment
for me was when
Bruce decided to go on the Reunion
Tour with the E Street Band
just around the millennium and the
boys, they hit Copenhagen as well.
And I was here. It was one
of those nights to remember.
I remember during
the encore of the show,
Bruce decides to
play Blood Brothers,
beautiful song, beautiful song.
And during the
last verse of the song,
the guy next to me...
I don't know his name.
I'd never seen him before.
I haven't seen him since.
He decides to
put his arm around me.
You know, all of a sudden, this
big guy has his arm around me.
And it was just one of those moments
where it didn't seem weird at all.
♪ On through the
houses of the dead
♪ Past those fallen
in their tracks
♪ We're always moving ahead
♪ And never looking back
Let's sing.
♪ Now we're out e on this road
♪ All along this road tonight
♪ Close my eyes and feel
so many friends around me
♪ In the early evening ligt
♪ And the miles we have come
♪ And the battles won and lost
♪ Are just so many
roads traveled
♪ So many rivers crossed
♪ And I ask God
for the strength
♪ And faith in one anothr
♪ 'Cause it's a good nigt for a ride
across this river to the other side
♪ My blood brothers
I remember walking home
after the show with my girl
and she said to me, "At some point, I
felt like I was the only one there. "
"I felt like he
was playing for me. "
And I said, "I know. I know exactly
what you're talking about. I know. "
Hello. My name is Jane.
I'm living in Helsingor, in
Denmark, just a small town.
This is the first time I've
ever tried to make a video
from my camera,
so this is not very good.
However, I wish to say
something about me and Bruce.
We have been friends
ever since 1985,
though he do not know me.
I have listened to his music
every day since '85.
I know the lyrics.
I know the music.
Every day when I go home for work,
I hear his records in my car.
I sort of relax.
I sort of get in a very good
mood when I listen to Bruce.
It doesn't matter whether it is
the new music or the old music.
I just love listening
to his music.
I'm not the kind of fan who
knows the size of his shoes,
or the names of his children,
although I know he has three children
and he has a lovely wife Patti.
Which is also...
She has a wonderful vocal.
And, of course, I understand
why he loves his woman.
One of the best music I have
heard him sing is the...
Red Headed Woman.
It is the kind of song that a man
who really loves his woman has made
and it must be wonderful to be
Patti to receive such a song.
I don't know what to say. I'm the
kind of fan who has attended
all his concerts
since '85 here in Denmark.
I always stand in the first
row, screaming and shouting
and dancing like a teenager
to a Beatles' concert.
This summer I was that lucky
that finally, after all
these years, I touched him.
We touched each other twice
in Roskilde in Denmark
and I cried like... I wept
because it was so big.
It's a great song about a great
subject, cunnilingus. That's right.
Yeah. I hope I'm pronouncing
that correctly.
Yeah, as I like to say, if you can
pronounce it, you can probably do it.
That's right.
And what can I say about it?
It's a college town.
There's probably people
practicing cunnilingus out there
as we speak tonight.
I hope so
and I do mean practicing,
because you young
whipper-snappers,
it takes a while to get that
under your belt.
It's like balancing a plate
on the end of your nose.
It's not as easy as it looks.
It takes some dedication,
it takes discipline,
attention to craft and detail.
That's right.
It takes... Yes.
It takes patience, patience
and more patience.
As I usually say.
But anyway
to not get into the whole
Freudian complications
of moving from one song
into the other.
We'll just leave
that alone, right?
Whoo! What can I say?
Where was I?
Oh, if there are
any kids out there,
cunnilingus is Latin for "It's
nice to keep your room very neat. "
♪ Well, brunettes are fine,
man, blondes are fun
♪ But when it comes to
getting the dirty job done
♪ I'll take
a red-headed woman
♪ It takes
♪ To get a dirty job done
♪ Well, listen up, stud
Your life's been wasted
♪ Till you've got down
on your knees and tasted
♪ A red-headed woman
♪ It takes a red-headed woman
♪ To get that dirty job
done That's right ♪
I hadn't been to a ton
of rock 'n' roll yet,
but I'd seen my share of shows.
And I understood in some way
that what I was witnessing
was something far beyond me
and my world as I knew it.
I was way too in the moment to
know that my life was changing,
but I did know that with each song,
I was leaving something behind.
The really critical
departure happened during
the long soul-shaking
instrumental in Jungleland.
He turned his back to us and
he walked towards the drum.
He swayed and he danced to the sax,
the bass, the organ, the piano.
He was young and taut
and all that man and men
and song and sound
became something bigger
and more powerful than anything
I understood or knew yet
in my young body.
And it was something
about rock 'n' roll and sex
and men and music and myself
and I grew a few years
and a few inches
when that incredibly beautiful
man had his perfect body
moving perfectly to
that crazy, sexy, sad song.
Everyone was totally
transfixed, tranced out.
I don't know if
anybody else was there,
but it was like the genie had
been let out of the bottle
and for me there
was no going back.
I think I cried.
I must have.
I was ripped out of my skin.
I was ripped out of my senses.
It was like the thunderbird had
swooped and had me in its talons.
And then someone behind me
lifts me up onto the stage,
really gently,
just lifts me up,
and I stand up and I'm standing
right there next to him.
And I'm so close I can see
the sweat through his jeans
and his dirty Converse.
And I look at him and he's
looking at me and he smiles
and I sort of moved to the side
and the next thing
I know someone comes
and really gently lowers me back
down to where I was before.
And I look around and there are
men all around me smiling.
I'm soaked to the skin
and I'm wearing red satin.
♪ The midnight gang's assembled
♪ And picked a rendezvous
for the night
♪ They'll meet 'neh
that giant Exxon sn
♪ That brings
this fair city light
♪ Man there's an opera
out on the Turnpike
♪ There's a ballet beig
fought out in the alley
♪ Until the local cops
Cherry Tops
♪ Rips this holy night
♪ The street's alive
As secret debts are d
♪ Contacts made,
they vanish unsen
♪ Kids flash guitars
just like switch-blades
♪ Hustling for
the record machine
♪ The hungry and the hunted
♪ Explode into
rock'n'roll bands
♪ That face off against
each other out in the street♪
He's a very
important figure to me.
He tells me that it's okay
to be what you want to be.
You can be... You can have a master's
degree and be a truck driver.
You can, you know, do what
you want, explore the world
and disregard
people's stereotypes
and expectations, because that's
what he is to me, you know?
He is rock 'n' roll.
He is country.
He is a sex symbol.
He is patriotic.
He is political, but poetic
at the same time and...
Yeah, I think he's someone
that I really look up to.
♪ I was tryin' to
find my way home
♪ But all I heard was a drone
♪ Bouncing off a satellie
♪ Crushin' the last
lone American night
♪ This is radio nowhere
♪ Is there anybody
alive out there?
♪ Radio nowhere
♪ Is there anybody
alive out there?
♪ I was spinning
'round a dead dial
♪ Just another
lost number in a file
♪ Dancin' down a dark hoe
♪ Just searchin' for
a world with some soul
♪ Radio nowhere
♪ Is there anybody
alive out there?
♪ Radio nowhere
♪ Is there anybody
alive out there?
alive out there? ♪
What would you say
to Bruce if you met him?
Shorten your concerts.
Three and a half hours.
I think that relationships
have been brought together
and then folded before you've
actually finished your concert.
It's just too long.
For the people who are there
for their loved ones,
it's quite a long
period of time.
I'm thinking. "What time
does the last train leave?"
"You know, how can I make this
picnic that I've brought last?"
You know, it's things like
that that really matter to me.
The night before this
happened, I was so broke
that I had to sleep
in a public park.
And then 12 hours late, I'm standing
with my guitar from the street,
getting ready to play some cafes and
this guy comes up to me and says,
"Hey, Bruce is coming
down the street. "
And I said, "Oh, yeah. "
Just another hero for me.
Didn't really believe it, but
then I looked across the street
and I see Bruce out there and
this tall black man with him
and that was Clarence Clemons
and I said, "Well... "
I shouted out, "Hey, Bruce, why don't
you come and play us the real thing?"
He kind of looked at me and
thought it was just funny
and then I said again,
"Hey, come on. "
And then he made a U-turn.
He came across the street.
And that's where this picture
started happening here.
I handed him one of the guitars
and he starts here
on the song I'm on Fire.
♪ Hey little girl
is your daddy home
♪ Did he go and
leave you all alone
♪ I got a bad desire
♪ Oh-oh-oh, I'm on fire
And I said, "Hey, I got to
do something for my family. "
I saw there was a video
camera across, you know,
so I came behind him.
♪ Oh-oh-oh, I'm on fire
I was kind of nervous about
what he would feel about it,
but I kind of said, "Well,
hey, he should be cool enough",
"you know, and this is the street.
We're all kings on the street. "
"There's nobody
above another there. "
And it's kind of hard to
believe ths was all happening.
There was a crowd in front,
you know, and...
You never can tell
what happens in life.
You never can tell.
It was amazing.
What do you know?
We got on with it for I think it
was 15 minutes and 17 seconds.
So, they say every man has 15
minutes of fame in his life.
I went a bit overboard.
♪ Even if we're just
dancing in the dark
dancing in the dark ♪
I didn't really realize
what had happened.
It was kind of...
It was kind of too qui.
Then the day after I was on the
front pe singing with Bruce.
This is a great thg
that such a big man
would come and step down
and give, you know...
He wasn't... He was just
one of us, you know.
Okay, he had had success, but
he was still just one of us
and that's what I really
loved about it, you know.
I really loved that.
We just said goodbye to one another
and he went his way and I went mine.
It was exactly how it should
happen on the street, you know.
Hi, my name is Gillian.
Hi, my name's Gillian.
Hi, my name's Gillian
and I'm a pretty big...
I'm a...
Hi, my name's Gillian and I'm a
pretty big Bruce Springsteen fan.
After my first
Bruce brought... Hi.
No.
Hi. My name's Gillian and I'm a
pretty big Bruce Springsteen fan.
After my first
Bruce concert in April,
I was so excited
and so full of emotion
and I wanted to let Bruce know
how important he was to me,
so I wrote him a letter, thinking
I'd be able to send it to him,
but I couldn't find
a fan mail address.
So I wrote it anyway
and just put it out there
in case I'd ever have the chance
to tell him how important he is
and his music is in my life.
So this is the perfect
opportunity for that,
so I'm going to share
that letter now.
Dear Bruce, to say
I am a fan of yours
would be quite
an understatement.
Your music is woven
into my very being.
It has become a part
of the story of me,
turning into a kind of soundtrack of
the past couple of years of my life.
I first discovered your
music about four years ago.
I heard Glory Days on the radio
and I guess it spoke to me
and to where I was
at that point in my life.
I started looking
at more of your songs
and my parents were quite amused
that I was suddenly listening
to music from their time.
But that's the thing, Bruce, your
music doesn't have a time or a place.
Your music is a story and it
bends and flows into the stories
of everyone who listens to it.
I guess what I'm trying
to say is thank you.
It seems like every time
I hit a bump in life,
I turn to you
and to your songs.
They pick me up and dust me
off in a way that no one
and nothing else can.
We all go through
dark times in life
and sometimes things
aren't going to get better
and they're not going
to be all right.
In those times, music can
be the best companion,
because it reminds you there can
still be beauty in this world
and that all is not lost
in spite of it all.
Without you, I would be lost.
Thank you.
Thanks, Bruce.
Thanks so much.
Thank you.
Thank you, Bruce.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for the music, boss.
Thank you, Bruce.
We love you.
Thanks, Bruce.
And thank you for everything.
Thank you from
the bottom of my heart.
So thank you, Bruce.
Thank you for your music.
Thank you, Bruce.
Thanks, Bruce.
Thank you.
Thank you, Bruce.
Thanks.
Thank you, Bruce. Thank you
for your amazing music.
I just want to say thanks.
Thanks, Bruce.
Thank you, Bruce.
Thank you so much.
Cheers, boss.
Merci,Bruce.
From the deepest part
of my heart, thank you.
It was nice being alone
with you tonight.
♪ In the day we sweat
it out on the streets
♪ Of a runaway American dream
♪ At night we ride
through the mansions of gly
♪ In suicide machines
♪ Sprung from cages
out on highway 9
♪ Chrome wheeled, fuel injected,
and steppin' out over the line
♪ Whoa, baby this town rips
the bones from your back
♪ It's a death trap,
it's a suicide rap
♪ We gotta get out
while we're young
♪ 'Cause tramps like us,
baby we were born to run
♪ Wendy let me in
I wanna be your friend
♪ I want to guard
your dreams and visions
♪ Just wrap your legs
'round these velvet rims
♪ And strap your hans
'cross my engines
♪ Together we could
break this trap
♪ We'll run till we drop,
baby we'll never go back
♪ Whoa, will you walk
with me out on the wire
♪ Cause baby I'm just
'a scared and lonely rider
♪ But I gotta knw how it feels
♪ I want to know if love is wild
I want to know if love is real
♪ Can you show me?
One, two, three!
♪ Beyond the palace
hemi-powered drones
♪ Scream down the boulevard
♪ Girls comb their hr
in rearview mirrors
♪ And the boys
try to look so hard
♪ The amusement park
rises bold and stark
♪ Kids are huddled
on the beach in a mist
♪ I wanna die with you
Wendy on the street tonight
♪ In an everlasting kiss
One, two, three!
♪ The highway's jammed
with broken heroes
♪ On a last chance power drive
♪ Everybody's out
on the run tonight
♪ But there's no
place left to hide
♪ Together Wendy we can
live with the sadness
♪ I'll love you with alle
madness in my soul
♪ Whoa, someday girl
I don't know when
♪ We're gonna get to that place
♪ Where we really wanna o
♪ And we'll walk in the sun
♪ But till then tramps like us
♪ Baby we were born to rn
♪ Tramps like us
♪ Baby we were born to run
♪ I've been knocking on the
door that holds the throne
♪ I've been looking for the
map that leads me home
♪ I've been stumbling on
good hearts turned to ste
♪ The road of good intentis
has gone dry as bone
♪ We take care of our own
♪ Wherever this flag's flon
♪ From Chicago to New Orleans
♪ From the muscle to the bone
♪ From the shotgun shack
to the Super Dome
♪ There ain't no help,
the cavalry stayed home
♪ There ain't no one
hearing the bugle blowin'
♪ We take care of our own
♪ Wherever this flag's flon
♪ Where're the eyes,
the eyes with the will to e
♪ Where's the hearts
that run over with mercy
♪ Where's the love that
has not forsaken me
♪ Where's the work that'll
set my hands, my soul free
♪ Where's the spirit
to reign rain over me
♪ Where's the promise,
from sea to shining sea
♪ Wherever this flag is flown
♪ We take care of our own