Come children. On
your way to school.
- Good morning mother Goose.
- Good morning.
Here you are, balloons.
All colors of the rainbow.
Boys! Boys!
Oh these kids will
be the death of me.
Bo Peep.
I'm coming mother.
Oh you children will
be the death of me.
Ah, mother, do you
really mean that?
Of course I don't.
Now you run right along
and tend to your sheep.
And don't go
losing them again.
I won't.
Come on fleecy, come
on curly, come on wooly.
How do you do my
dear Sra. Peep.
How do you do, Sr. Barnaby?
And how is your charming
daughter, Ms. Bo Peep?
Very well thank you.
Then, may I be permitted
to pay my respects?
Sorry, but she's out
tending her sheep.
Thank you.
Good morning my pretty
little butterfly.
Good morning Sr. Barnaby!
I bring you a little bouquet
A fragrant token
of my deep devotion.
Thank you very
much Sr. Barnaby.
And now I have to leave
you sir. My my sheep
Nay!
I have long admired you.
Deep with wonder on your
sweet and maidenly virtue.
Marveled at your
tender loveliness.
In short
I'm asking you
to become my wife.
I
I'm sorry Sr. Barnaby
and I hope you won't
think me ungrateful
- but
- I'm a very rich man my dear.
Please!
Think carefully, child.
Lest I revert
to other means.
That would be an ugly
way to win a pretty wife.
I wouldn't marry you if you
were young, which you can't be
if you were honest,
which you never were
and if you were about to die tomorrow
which is too much to hope for.
We shall meet again my
pretty little buttercup.
And then you will
sing a different tune.
Fleecy, Curly!
I came back to remind you that
your little financial obligation
You mean the mortgage?
is due today.
Couldn't you give me
just a little more time?
I'm sorry. The law
must take it's course.
I shall be back shortly.
Come boys.
You'll be late for work.
We're coming.
Good morning, mother Peep.
Good morning, Ollie!
Will you come on.
It's almost 8 O'clock.
Why, I thought I left you
upstairs in the bedroom.
You did.
Well how'd you
get down here?
I fell out the window.
Good morning mother Peep.
God morgen Stannie.
Good morning Ollie.
God morgen Stan never
mind good morning.
Come on and let's go!
Wait a minute. I
forgot something.
I'll be right down.
Will you come on. Do you
want us to be late for work?
Don't forget
your lunch, Ollie.
What's the matter,
mother Peep?
I've got bad news for you.
Bad news?!
I'm afraid you two boys will have
to find some other place to live.
Well what do you mean?
That old stingely Barnaby holds
the mortgage against this shoe.
It's due today
and I haven't got
the money to pay him.
And we'll all be cast
out into the street.
Stannie. Go upstairs
and get my money box.
Eh?
Go get my money box.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to give
you all of my savings.
And I'll get the rest of it
from our master the toy maker.
No ones going to throw
you out of this shoe.
Oh I can't let you
do such a thing.
Tut, tut, tut, tarut!
One good turn
deserves another.
Now smile!
That's it that's it.
I owe you 1.48. Stannie Dum
I borrowed it.
I know you borrowed it.
But what did you
borrow it for?!
Well you see I had to
buy some more Pee wee's.
I lost three of them playing
with little Jack Horner.
Had to buy some
more Pee Wee's.
Well don't you
mind, Mother Peep
I'll get the full amount
from the toy maker.
Oh you boys musn't go
into debt on my account.
Listen, when the toy maker finds out
that Barnaby's up to his old tricks again
he'll give me the full
amount without any problem.
Oh, can I depend on that?
Why of course you can.
You know the toy maker
and I are just like that.
Aren't we, Stannie?
Are you?
Why certainly.
Hvem af jer?
- Which is you?
- Why this one right never mind!
- Good bye.
Don't forget your lunch.
And don't you worry.
No I won't.
Good bye boys.
Just a moment.
What is this Pee Wee business
you've been spending all my money on?
Would you like to see it?
Certainly I'd like to see it.
After all the money it's cost me
I think I'm entitled to
know what it's all about.
Alright, look.
What do you think of that?
Piffle!
That's the silliest
thing I have ever seen.
Try it.
I don't want to try it!
Why, can't you do it?
Well certainly I can. What
do you mean, can't I do it
Give me that!
Get over there.
It's a certainty that
anything you can do I can do!
What for instance?
Here!
Just a moment!
Thank you!
Come on, we'll
be late for work.
Say listen when you
get that money from the
toy maker will you borrow
a little extra for me?
Well I lost me Pee Wee and
I'll have to get some more.
Get in here now,
will you. Pee Wee!
Good morning, master.
What do you mean,
good morning?!
You know you're
half an hour late!
If this happens again, it
will mean instant dismissal.
Get to work!
Say, aren't you gonna ask him about
the money to pay off the mortgage?
I can't ask him now. Don't you
see what a bad humor he's in.
Well if we don't get that
money, Mother Peep's gonna be
turned out of the shoe and she
won't have any place to sleep.
We can't let her do that.
Why if I ask him now, he'll
jump right down my throat.
But I thought you and
he were just like that.
We are!
Well why don't you ask him?
Why don't you ask him?
Well I can't ask him.
Why?
Well he and I are
just like that.
Oh, don't be silly.
He likes you better
than he does me.
Does he?
Yep. He told me he did!
- Did he?
- Yeah!
Oh master.
What?
Ollie wants to speak to you.
Well, what is it?
Well could I speak to
you privately please sir?
I've got a very important
question I want to ask you.
Don't bother me now!
Can't you see that I'm
busy?! Go on with your work!
Well if you knew how important it
was, you'd see me privately because if
Will you shut up and
go on with your work!
Fleecy fleecy!
Wooly snowball?!
No, I haven't seen them!
Oh, Tom Tom.
I don't know what mother would
do if they were really lost.
Oh, don't worry.
They'll be found.
You've lost them
before, haven't you?
Matter of fact, last month
you lost them five times!
Oh I couldn't have.
Yes you did.
And four times the
month before that!
You see, you're
getting worse.
What you need is someone to help
you look after the darn things.
Who, for instance?
Oh, he'd have to
be most unusual.
Energetic resourceful
and with any
amount of patience.
A fellow sort of well
Like me!
Not interested?
Not even a little bit?
Then I'll just keep you there
until you are interested!
- Nice? Interested?
- Uh huh.
Oh look Tom Tom,
they found them!
You should hang your
head you naughty sheep.
My dear friends
and citizens of Toyland.
I want you all to meet
The future Sra. Piper!
Hello mister toy maker.
Well, how's my
order coming along?
Everything is in fine shape.
- Good.
- Are you coming in?
Yes, just a moment.
Alright. I won't forget
you. Now run along.
Hello everybody.
How's everything?
And how are my two boys?
Hello Sr. Santee.
Can't wait until you see the
wooden soldiers we made for you.
The finest piece of work
we've ever turned out.
Splendid!
Ollie! Go and bring
one of them in.
Yes sir. You'd better
help me. They're heavy.
We'll have them
right out, Sr. Santee.
You'll get the
surprise of your life!
Don't try to lift it. All you have
to do is press the button in the back
And it walks out by itself.
Isn't it wonderful?
It does everything but talk.
Wonderful yes. But
not what I ordered.
What do you mean?
I ordered 600 soldiers
at one foot high.
What?
You took that order.
What was it?
I thought you said 100
soldiers at six foot high.
You got the order all wrong.
I couldn't give those things
to my children to play with.
Put it back in the box and get
out of here. You're through!
Here's another mess
you've gotten us into.
Well I couldn't help it.
If you had been watching what you were
doing, you wouldn't have gotten us into
Come out of there.
Not you! It's for him!
Put that thing back in
the box! Get out of here!
Stop it! Stop
it! Do something!
Come out of there!
Why didn't you stop it,
you blithering idiots?!
Now get out and stay out!
Yes sir.
Aren't you gonna ask him about
the money for the mortgage?
What's that?!
Just skip it. It's a fine
time to ask for money.
Oh mommy. I'm so happy!
Tom Tom has asked me
to become his bride.
My child.
And with your permission,
we'd like to be married.
Why of course darling.
My blessings are with you.
And may nothing ever happen
to mar your happiness.
Ah, thank you mother.
Sr. Barnaby!
When you enter my house,
I'll trouble you to knock.
Your house, my good lady?
Did you say your house?
Yes, my house!
Not until this little
debt is fulfilled.
Why mother, what
does it mean?
It means my dear
that unless this
mortgage is paid
You will all be thrown
out into the street.
Of course
We could compromise.
Compromise?
Yes.
Should your daughter
reconsider my generous offer
to become my wife
we could forget
this little matter.
And it could be
her wedding present.
Mother?!
Don't worry darling nothing
like that will ever happen.
Then, let us get
down to business.
Sr. Barnaby!
You can make
out your receipt.
You'll be paid in
full, right now!
Well, here you are boys.
Just in time.
This wretched man seems to think that we
haven't got the money to pay off the mortgage.
But we have, haven't we!
Haven't we boys!
Why what's the matter?
Didn't you get the money?
No, you see Ollie
made a mistake.
A mistake?
He and the toy maker
are not like that.
Are you!?
Then I take it madam
You cannot meet your
lawful obligation?
In which case, I
shall bid you good day.
Foreclosure papers will
be served in due course.
Oh, your not really going
to throw us into the street?
Much as it pains
me, I'm sorry.
Big bait catches big rats!
Oh mother, what shall I do?
If only he didn't
have that mortgage.
Don't you worry, Mother Peep
Stannie and me will find a way to get
the mortgage from that old buzzard!
He sure is an old buzzard.
You know, if he thinks he's gonna throw
this shoe into the street, he's mistaken.
He certainly is.
You know what
I'd like to do.
What?
I'd like to put on this shoe
and kick him right in the pants.
Then I'd kick
What happened?
Barnaby clunked you.
Open that window.
- Ollie?
- What?
We're outside.
Good!
Now what do we do?
Take me over to Barnaby's house
and be sure no one sees you.
Ok.
And be careful!
We're here.
So far, so good.
It wasn't so far.
We just came
across the street.
Ring the bell!
It wasn't so far! Hmph!
Who is it?
It's me.
What do you want at
this hour of the night?
Well you see, Ollie and I are sorry
for what happened this afternoon
And just to show you we're not mad at
you, we brought you a Christmas present.
It's from me,
and from Ollie.
Christmas present
in the middle of July?
Oh yes, you see we always do
our Christmas shopping early.
If you'll open the door I'll
bring it right in for you.
I'll be right down.
He's coming down. He's
going to let us in.
That's fine.
Now don't forget
when he goes to bed
you give me the signal.
And I'll get out of the box,
open the door and let you in.
Then we'll get the mortgage.
So far, so good.
Ah, what is it?
- I couldn't tell you.
- Couldn't?
No. You see it's a surprise.
And it musn't be
opened til Christmas.
See.
Do not open,
until Christmas.
Well, that's
very nice of you.
It is, isn't it!
Well, good night
Sr. Barnaby.
Good night Sr. Dum.
You can go to bed now.
Thank you
Sr.
Dum.
Merry Christmas.
A merry Christmas to you.
Good night.
Good night!
Good night Ollie!
Good night Stannie!
Where as Ollie Dee and Stannie Dum
have been found guilty of burglary
they will be dunked and thereafter
exiled to bogey land forever!
Good night Ollie!
Your majesty what
are we waiting for?
Oh yeah proceed
with the dunking!
Come on!
Your first. Come on!
- Ollie!
- What?
You better give me your watch. I'll
hold it for you until you come out.
Thanks. Now take good care of it because
I wouldn't have anything happen to that.
- I will.
- Good bye.
Good bye.
- Come on!
- All right.
Splendid!
- Is it cold?
- Yes!
I'm smothering!
- Keep your nose closed!
- I will!
Hurry. He'll die of ammonia!
This is terrible.
Hold your nose, Ollie!
Bring him up.
How do you feel?
You know how I feel!
Here, have a drink of
water. That'll do you good.
Haven't I had enough water?!
I was only trying to help.
Sr. Barnaby. Can't something
be done to stop this?
Why yes. Consent
to become my wife.
And they will go free.
All right, Sr. Barnaby.
I consent.
With your majesty's permission.
I wish to withdraw my charges.
Withdrawn they shall be.
Residents of Toyland
I want you all to meet
The future Senhora.
Silas Barnaby.
You may go.
Thank you sir.
- Does that mean we're free?
- Yes.
And from now on, you and I are
going to be very close friends.
- Does that mean that he won't be dunked!?
- Yes!
- Isn't that nice?
- What?
He and I are just like that.
And I don't have to get wet.
Oh, is that so!
- Ollie!
- What?
Here's your watch.
Run over and tell the bride that all is
in readyness and her lover is waiting.
Mumsy, what did Tom Tom say?
He understands.
Now you see. If you hadn't said good
night Ollie, this wouldn't have happened.
Where are you
going Mother Peep?
I'm going over to Barnaby
to make a final plea.
Surely there must be one spark of
kindness in that phony heart of his.
That's a good ideia. But I
don't think it will do any good.
You're right Ollie. You
can't turn blood into a stone.
What do you mean?
Well her talking to Barnaby
is just a matter of pouring one ear into
another and coming out the other side.
It can't be done.
I'm sorry Bo Peep that you had
to choose me for the best man.
Why I'd rather do anything in this
world than to have to give you away.
Why Stannie is so upset, he's
not even going to the wedding.
You are upset, aren't you!
Upset?! I'm house broken.
Not house broken.
He means heart broken.
House broken huh!
Come in.
Sr. Barnaby. Don't force my
daughter into this dreadful marriage.
I'm an old woman. Pleading
for her daughter's happiness.
Oh don't do this
dreadful thing.
Sr. Barnaby. I'll
do anything you ask!
Work for you. Slave for you.
Only don't please don't.
Woman, you're a fool!
The bargains made and
you'll abide by it.
Master, the bride is here!
Welcome to Barnaby Hall.
Shut that door!
Come, come judge.
Let's waste no time.
Have you the ring?
Your name is Silas Barnaby?
It is.
And your name is
Little Bo Peep?
It is.
Do you take this woman for
you lawfully wedded wife?
I do.
And do you take this man for
your lawfully wedded husband?
I do.
I now pronounce
you man and wife.
And now, to kiss the bride.
Just a moment.
Haven't you forgotten
something, Sr. Barnaby?
Oh yes. The mortgage.
My wedding present.
Now, you may kiss the bride.
What is the
meaning of this?!
Big bait, catches big rats!
The king shall hear of this!
Tom Tom.
Oh my boys!
That sure was a
good ideia of yours.
It certainly was!
Well good bye!
And good luck.
What do you mean, good bye?
Aren't I going with you?
Why no.
You have to stay
here with Barnaby.
Your married to him.
I don't want to
stay here with him.
Why?
I don't love him!
Well don't worry. Old Barnaby
will never bother us again.
- Because I'm going to take you away.
- Where?
Tricked! Cheated!
Laughed at in the streets!
Fools!
So they think they can
outwit old Barnaby, eh.
I'll show them.
There must be a way.
There must be some way!
Idiot! Dolt! Imbecile! Pig!
Pig!
Get me a nice red juicy apple. I'll
steal one of the three little pigs.
And the evidence will be
placed in Tom Tom's house.
You know the penalty
for pig-napping?
Banishment to Bogeyland!
Sit still!
Take this evidence and
place it in Tom Tom's house.
Master. Why the sausage?
That will prove that
he not only stole the
pig, but that he also
ground him into sausage.
And now little Elmer
We shall see.
Whereas Tom-Tom Piper has
been found guilty of pignapping
He will be immediately
banished to Bogeyland.
Poor Tom Tom.
I'm sure glad we didn't
have to go to Bogeyland.
So am I.
What happens to
you in Bogeyland?
Oh it's a terrible place.
Once you go there,
you never come back.
Why?
Well, when the Bogeyman
gets you, they eat you alive!
What do they look like?
Well I've heard that they're
half man, and half animal.
With great big ears
and great big mouths.
And hair all
over their body.
And long claws that
they catch you with.
Scat! Go on!
Tom my boy you knew the penalty
for pinapping. Why did you do it?
But I didn't do it!
I don't even know what
you're talking about.
How can you say that
in view of this evidence
found in your house.
Take it away.
Your majesty. You made
a horrible mistake.
Tom Tom knows
nothing about this.
He's been with me all
day. Hasn't he mommy!
That's right your majesty.
Why not let the law take
it's course, your majesty?!
Watch that until
I come back!
What does that mean?
Exhibit B.
That means that the pig
sausage is part of the evidence.
Doesn't taste like
pig sausage to me!
What does it taste like?
Tastes like pork.
Try it.
Why that's neither
pig nor pork!
- It's beef!
- Beef?!
I smell a rat!
Barnaby's got
a hand in that.
I believe that little
Elmer is still alive!
Come on, we'll find out!
You've got to make them hear me
your majesty, you've got to hear.
Tom Tom knows
nothing about this.
The little pigs
are friends of ours.
Why should he
want to hurt them?
The violin and hat were in
the house when we got home.
He's innocent I
tell you, innocent!
It is with deep regret that I have
to enforce the law of our kingdom.
Take him away!
I tell you I'm innocent!
- I didn't steal the pig!
- Tom Tom Tom Tom
You see child it
was folly wasting
your affections on
a common pignapper.
Let me go! Let me go!
Tom Tom is innocent
and you know it!
I hate you! I hate you!
Just a minute!
Silence!
Sr. Majesty. Tom
Tom is innocent!
We found little Elmer
in Barnaby's cellar!
Let's get him!
I'll give 50,000 Guineaus for the
capture of Barnaby dead or alive!
Dead or alive?!
Dead or alive!
Can't you make up your
mind which way you want him?
Take me to my tower.
Let's go around the
back way. We'll get him!
Alright Sr. Barnaby.
There's no use hiding!
We know where you are!
You better come out, because if you don't
we're gonna stay right here until you do.
Even if it takes all night!
Are we gonna stay
here all night?
No! We're gonna make
him think we are.
Tom Tom!
- Tom Tom!
- Bo Peep!
Stan and Ollie found
little Elmer, alive!
Where?
In Barnaby's cellar.
I knew he had something
to do with this!
Oh if I ever get
my hands on him.
Come on. We'll find
our way out of here.
Oh Tom Tom, we'll never
find our way out of here!
Oh yes we will! Come on!
- Did he come up?
- No!
Are you coming up?
You better come
up, dead or alive!
How can he come up
dead when he's alive?
Let's drop a rock on him, then
we'll make him dead when he's alive.
Now your talking sense.
- Look out!
- Don't tell him to look out!
- It might have hit him.
- That's what I wanted to do!
Did it hit you?
- Not a sound.
- It must have got him.
Go down and bring him up.
You go down and
bring him up.
Do you mean to tell me that you're going to
let 50,000 Guineas slip right thru your fingers?
Well I'm scared!
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
You and he are
just like that!
Well that was before
we were married.
All right. I'll compromise.
We'll both go down.
That's better.
Go ahead.
Wait a minute go ahead!
I'll teach you to trifle
with Barnaby Silas!
- You know what?
- What?
He's not here.
I can see he's not here!
Oh look! Maybe he
went through this way.
I'll bet he did.
Let's go see.
I wonder where he went?
We'll soon find out.
Let's go that way.
There he is!
Sr. Barnaby! You're
going back with us
Oh the Bogeymen!
I can't get help! help!
They've escaped me.
But I'll get them if I have
to destroy all of Toyland!
To the rafts!
Stand back! Here
comes the king.
Why all the commotion!?
Have you no reverence
for my beauty sleep?!
Sorry your majesty but
we were celebrating the
rescue of Tom Tom and
Bo Peep from Bogeyland.
Splendid news!
And who had the
courage to do this?
They did sir.
Did you get Barnaby?
No sir! He was running so
fast, we couldn't catch him.
- He was scared to
death, wasn't he?
He sure was!
Well tell me all about it.
Stannie and me
chased Barnaby and the
Bogeyman so far
they'll never come back!
What do these
Bogeyman look like?
Oh they're terrible looking!
They're half man
and half animal!
With great big ears
great big mouths
and long claws
- Come back!
- You don't have to run away!
- Nothing to be afraid of!
- You're not scared now!
They're not half
as bad as they look!
There they are!
Follow me!
Break in the door!
- Here!
- What are you going to do?
We'll fix those
Bogeymen! Come on!
Come on now!
- Say, you know what!
- What?
- Let's load them in the cannon!
- Fine!
Get some more darts!
- You know what!
- What?
The wooden soldiers!
Let's get the cannon and
give them a parting shot!