Our state fair is a
great state fair
Don't miss it
Don't even be late
It's dollars to doughnuts
that our state fair
Is the best state fair in our state
Our state fair is a
great state fair
Don't miss it
Don't even be late
It's dollars to doughnuts
that our state fair
Is the best state fair in our state
Take it easy, Blue Boy. Your
supper will be here any minute.
I wish I knew what was
keeping that feller.
Our state fair is a
great state fair
Don't miss it
Don't even be late
It's dollars to doughnuts
that our state fair
Is the best state fair in our state
Dad! Daddy, I just had
Mr. Cramer on the phone.
He said Dave Miller stopped
by his place 10 minutes ago
- to put water in his radiator.
- Thanks, daughter.
Margy?
- Have you finished your packing?
- Not yet. I was just going to.
I don't know what's got into you lately.
All you do is sit around and mope.
I don't sit around and mope.
Well, stop moping now and
finish your packing.
Always saying she doesn't
know what's got into me.
I'll be glad to get to the fair,
hear something different, see
something different for a change.
What has got into me, anyway?
The things I used to like
I don't like anymore
I want a lot of other things
I've never had before
It's just like Mother says
I sit around and mope
Pretending I am wonderful
And knowing I'm a dope
- Margy?
- Yes, Mother?
As soon as you're finished, I want you to
come down and help me with the pickles.
In a minute, Mother.
Pickles!
I'm as restless as a willow
In a windstorm
I'm as jumpy as a puppet
On a string
I'd say that I had spring fever
But I know it isn't spring
I'm starry-eyed and
vaguely discontented
Like a nightingale
without a song to sing
Oh, why should I have spring fever
When it isn't even spring
I keep wishing
I were somewhere else
Walking down a strange, new street
Hearing words that
I have never heard
From a man I've yet to meet
I'm as busy as a spider
Spinning daydreams
I'm as giddy as a baby on a swing
I haven't seen a
crocus or a rosebud
Ora robin on the wing
But I feel so gay
In a melancholy way
That it might as well be spring
It might as well be
Spring
Margy!
I'm coming, Mother.
Come on, boy.
Ah, he'll win first this year sure.
He's half again the hog
he was last year.
You don't really expect to win, do
you, with that animated lard can?
Say, listen, you can say
anything you please about me,
but don't say anything bad
about Blue Boy.
That's the finest Hampshire
boar that ever breathed.
If you think that, he's
just as good as beat now.
Be better if he was
third or fourth best.
- He'd stand a better chance.
- What are you talking about?
If a hog or a man ever got what
he was entitled to just once,
the eternal stars would quit
making melody in the spheres.
Oh, there you go
with that book talk again.
I say he's the best hog in the state,
and the judges will say so too.
They might.
But if that turns out good,
then something else
will probably happen.
- He might catch pneumonia...
- Oh!
or hog cholera,
or you might catch pneumonia.
Or something might happen
to Wayne or Margy.
Oh!
Mark my words, Abel, there's
compensation in this world.
For every good, there's bad. Now,
Ralph Waldo Emerson tells us...
I don't care what
Waldo Emerson tells us!
Look, I'll just make
a little bet with you.
- On what?
- I'll bet you we go to the fair...
and Blue Boy
will win the grand award.
And nothing bad will happen
to him, me or my family.
Yes, and we'll all have
a good time too
and be better off for it
after the fair is over.
It's a foolish bet, Abel. If you'd
asked me, I'd have given you 10-to-1.
But you didn't ask me,
so it's an even bet.
- Five dollars?
- Five dollars is right.
I'll be around for the money
the day you get back.
- Be around with the money, you mean.
- You'll see. You'll see.
Yeah, I'll see.
Well, well, what's this?
You got your chains on.
You expecting a shower?
Nope. I'm expecting good weather.
That's why I put my chains on,
so I wouldn't be fooled.
Do you want your name "Mrs. Abel
Frake" or "Mrs. Melissa Frake"?
Melissa Frake, I guess. With
your father entering Blue Boy,
the judges might get us mixed.
Hog cholera, pneumonia.
He left out earthquakes,
the old gloom spreader.
Poor Dad.
Mmm, I don't know.
Let me taste.
- Don't taste like Grandma Stidger's.
- I followed her recipe.
- I'll get it.
- You left something out.
Abel Frake, I am not gonna
put liquor into my cooking!
Making mincemeat without brandy?
No such thing.
I don't approve of it,
and I won't do it.
Well, you'll be sorry. You know,
those judges at the fair,
they like a little snifter
now and then.
- It's Eleanor, for Wayne.
- Wayne's out back somewhere.
I'll find him.
Why don't you say hello
to Eleanor, Ma?
See how her mother is. You know, they
had the doctor again this morning.
- I suppose I should.
- Find out if she's going to the fair.
Yes, I will.
Hello, Eleanor. How are you, dear?
How's your mother feeling?
Yes, I know. I'm sorry I couldn't
get by to see her today,
but I've been so busy getting
ready to leave and all.
Oh, well, I'm glad
she's better, dear.
Wayne'll be here any moment.
Just hold on.
And be sure to give
my love to your mother.
Thank you, dear. Good-bye.
- Abel?
- Hmm?
I need a good-sized box, or cotton.
Something to carry my pickles in.
Know just what you want, Ma.
I'll get it for you right away.
"Stir in apples and molasses,
spices, lemons..."
"Two parts good brandy."
No, I won't!
- Eph, where's Wayne?
- Wayne? He's back there in the barn.
Thank you, mister.
And now, I think I'll have a
try at that fancy brass clock.
Yes, that one.
- There ya are.
- Wayne?
There's a nice string of pearls.
I think I'll have a go at them.
- Oh, I know they're fakes, but...
- Wayne!
What are you doing?
- How long you been there?
- Just a little while.
Why didn't you say somethin'
instead of just standing there?
Who were you talking to?
And does Mother know you have
her embroidery hoops out here?
Look, just leave me alone, will ya?
And stop prying in other people's affairs.
Speaking of affairs,
Eleanor's on the phone.
Eleanor? Well, Christmas!
Why didn't you tell me?
Eleanor's on the phone.
Hello, Eleanor? Hi, honey. What'd the
doctor say about your mother? Can you go?
Well, I don't know
what to do, Wayne.
The doctor said she's
a little better, but...
Oh, but, Eleanor, you've got to go!
I've made a lot
of plans for us. What?
I keep wishing
I were somewhere else
Walking down a strange, new street
Hearing words
that I have never heard
From a man
I've yet to meet
He would be a kind
of handsome combination
Of Ronald Colman Charles Boyer
And Bing
Margy. My dear, little Margy.
I'd make the world a ruby for
your little finger and say,
"I love you.
I love you. I love you."
Ah, Margy. You are beautiful.
You are so very beautiful.
And we feel so gay
In a melancholy way
That it might as well be spring
Margy!
- Hello, Margy.
- Hello, Harry.
No, I'm not mad.
I'm just disappointed.
Well, I'll see you when I get back.
Good-bye.
Gee, I wish I was going to
the fair with you tonight.
I'd rather be doing that
than anything I know.
- Oh, would you, Harry?
- Well, sure.
- Only I can't neglect my cows.
- Oh. Of course not.
- Say, I saw something today.
- What?
The sweetest bit of farmland
this side of Davenport.
I was thinking of puttin' a
bid in on it if you like it.
- If I like it?
- Well, sure.
You know I haven't made a plan since I was
12 years old that didn't include you.
- Got a house on it?
- Yeah, but it's too old.
- We'd have to build a new one.
- Oh, I like old houses.
It wouldn't fit in
with our kind of farm.
You know, I plan to do everything my
old man won't let me do on his place.
Scientific irrigation, electric
milking, separate hen roosts.
No horses. All tractor power.
- You see what I mean? Everything modern.
- But the house you live in...
It's gotta be the same. No
clapboard and shingle business.
There's a new kind of
plastic, prefabricated job.
I want you to see it.
Got the catalog at home.
- Is it pretty?
- Sure!
But what's more important,
it's termite-proof.
Wait till you see it. And they
tell you how to furnish it too.
No rugs or carpets.
They're just dust collectors.
- What's on the floor?
- Linoleum through the whole house.
Wait till you see the pictures. It's slick
and smooth and easy to keep clean.
Well, it's like every room
in the house was a bathroom.
- Sounds real cozy.
- Yeah, don't it, though?
- What I've always wanted.
- Oh, sure. It's the only way to live.
- Everything's sanitary.
- Sure.
- And if we had children...
- Oh, Margy!
I said if by any strange
chance we had children,
why, I could dress them
in cellophane rompers.
Say, I didn't know they had...
Life will just be ducky...
In our air-conditioned
patent-leather farmhouse
Plastic.
On our ultramodern scientific farm
We'll live in a streamlined heaven
And we'll waste no time on charm
No geraniums to clutter our veranda
Nor a single, little
sentimental thing
No Virginia creepers
Nothing useless
- What's the matter, honey?
- Oh, nothing.
Just restless, I guess.
Sure. I understand.
You like to travel.
Well, I figured we'd make a little
trip, California or Bermuda or...
if it was May, we could go to
Washington, see the cherry trees.
- A honeymoon?
- That's what.
I'd almost marry you
to make the trip, Harry.
No kiddin' now, Margy. What do
you say? What do you say?
Well, I won't say anything
just now, Harry.
- Well, after the fair, maybe?
- Maybe.
Wow!
Look at him, Marge!
Holy cow! Gets bigger
every time I see him.
Biggest boar in the world, I bet.
All depends on how you spell it.
Eleanor can't go.
- Where's your mincemeat, Ma?
- Right here between my feet.
- Is the top on tight?
- Certainly, it's on tight.
- Why?
- Oh, nothin'.
Just don't want the flavor
to escape, that's all.
- Hello, Miss Frake!
- Hello, there!
- How are you?
- Just fine.
We'll come see you as
soon as we get settled.
Yes, do that.
If Wayne doesn't come back soon to
take me around, I'm going by myself.
I do wish your father
would come to his breakfast.
If he'd rather stay with Blue
Boy than eat, well, let him.
But I've got
my whole day planned out.
Don't you know you can't
plan out a whole day?
- There's no such thing.
- I do it all the time.
You sound just like Harry. He thinks
you can plan out your whole life.
So you can.
Is that what he was
talking about yesterday?
Uh-huh.
Did you come to anything definite?
Uh-uh.
I don't know
what you're waiting for.
It would serve you right if Harry up and
married that Skidmore girl instead of you.
I almost hope he does.
Me too.
Step right up, ladies
and gentlemen.
Move in a little closer.
Don't be afraid.
Hurry, hurry! Play the game!
Three rings for a dime.
Prizes worth up to $20.
Positively no blanks. The prize
you win is the prize you get,
the prize you take away.
Don't any gentleman
want to try his skill?
Ain't nobody here
got the pioneer spirit?
I tell you what I'm going to do.
I'm goin' to put down three nice,
new, crisp one-dollar bills.
One here, one here, and one here.
Now, who will spend a dime
for three chances at $3.00?
Is that real money?
If you win 'em and you
don't like 'em, buddy,
I'll give you
a dollar apiece for 'em.
Hey, mister,
them hoops look mighty small.
- Do they fit over those things?
- Lots of people do it, sir.
- Lots of people do it.
- Yeah, I did it last year.
Remember me? I won a
pearl-handled revolver.
Well, now, there. You see?
Young Mr. Daniel Boone here
won a revolver off me
right at this very fair a year ago.
Bring down any grizzly bears
with that shootin' iron, sonny?
Tell you what I'll do with you.
I'll just give you three rings on
the house to start things off.
Three chances for nothing.
I can't win. I can only lose.
But I love the game.
Remember, young man, you're
enjoying the courtesy of the house.
Don't cost us money.
I just lost $2.00!
But I'm having fun.
I love the game.
Here, my boy. I want you
to have a fair shake.
That ring looks warped.
Try this one.
This one's all right.
Well, well, you all see
how easy it is.
- Who else wants to try?
- I'll try again. Here's a dime.
- Who else wants a chance at a big prize?
- Here, mister, here's my dime.
How about you, sir? You look
like you've got a good aim.
- Why, you got a customer.
- Give me three rings. Here's my dime.
He's trying to dodge the boy!
- All right, buddy. Here ya are.
- You didn't put any dollar bills back.
Ain't pearl necklaces and safety
razors good enough for ya?
Can't you enjoy the game
for the game's sake?
Are ya money mad?
Those prizes are all fakes, but I'll
win 'em anyway just to prove it.
Quite a character.
Step up, folks.
We're havin' fun here.
Just lost a pearl necklace,
but I'm laughing.
I love the game.
Why, the young man
is winnin' a fortune.
- Here you are, buddy.
- Look, pot metal molded in one piece.
What good's a vanity case
it won't even open?
Okay, fella, you had your fun.
Now, come on. Move along.
And those clocks,
they don't have any works.
What good are they?
Listen, kid, you know what
I'm payin' for this pitch?
- No. What?
- More dough than you'll ever see.
So you spend a dime,
take $3.00 in cash
and then try to tell the
public my prizes are no good!
Well, they aren't.
They're just a lot of junk.
Look, you, I've been nice
just long enough.
- Now, beat it, or I'll call a policeman.
- Why don't you?
- What's that?
- I said, why don't you call a policeman?
He's only trying to bluff you.
The law says
he's got to sell you
all the rings you want.
- Otherwise, you can close up his place.
- Oh, a smart dame, huh?
A law student. Now, you listen
to me, Arsenic and Glamour,
- I don't know who you are...
- I'll tell you who I am.
My father's the chief
of police here.
- Your father is...
- The chief of police.
I was standing here
and saw the whole thing.
Say, how did you
get so good at this?
It's kind of a silly thing to be good at,
isn't it? But he made me sore last year.
I was trying for one of those
pearl-handled revolvers.
It cost me about $8.00. When I finally
did win it, it wasn't a revolver at all.
- It wouldn't even shoot. It was just a toy.
- Oh, ho!
- Defrauding the public, huh?
- Now, look, wait a minute.
I wouldn't have minded that so much,
but he kidded me in front of the crowd.
- So I...
- You practiced all year just to get even?
That's right. I figured I'd come back
and make as big a fool out of him
- as he made out of me.
- Oh, no, you don't.
Will you give him $8.00 back
if he promises to lay off?
- Look, you, I don't care who your father is.
- Okay.
Here. Here, here.
Here's your eight bucks,
and you don't come back, see?
- Is it a deal?
- Think it's all right to take it?
Well, sure, it's all right.
Here you are. Good-bye.
Good-bye!
Oh, don't leave, folks.
Prizes up to $20.
- Ah!
- Step right up, ladies and gentlemen!
We're having fun here!
Gee, it was swell of you to stand
up for me like that. Thanks.
Well, that's all right.
He had it coming to him.
Well, uh, now that you helped
me get my money back,
how about helping me spend it?
- No, that won't be necessary.
- What about a frozen custard?
- No, thank you. I believe not.
- Hot dog?
No. Really, I have an appointment.
I'm late already.
Won't I see you again? How about tonight?
Will you be on the midway?
Tonight? Yes, I think so.
I hope so.
I'll sure be looking for you.
- Do that. Good-bye.
- Good-bye.
You sure you won't change your mind?
How about some popcorn?
Get tickets now if
you care to ride.
Train's now ready to leave.
Get your tickets for this ride.
All aboard if you care to ride.
- The train is now...
- One, please.
Please get tickets for this ride.
It's the longest,
the highest, the fastest,
the safest ride at the fairground.
Get tickets now if
you care to ride.
Hey, Pappy, there aren't
any seats together.
Oh. Say, mister, do you mind
sitting in the seat behind?
Thanks a lot.
Thanks.
- All aboard!
- Okay. There they go! Hold your seats.
They're off on a race through
the clouds. A thrill a minute!
Sit down!
What are you trying to do,
get yourself killed?
I'm sorry.
Haven't you ever been on one
of these things before?
Not since I was a little girl.
- I used to be afraid of them.
- But you're not now.
That's what I wanted to find out.
Here comes another dip.
It's nearly over now.
Here's the tunnel.
Johnny, stop that!
Everybody out, folks.
Everybody out.
- I'm going around again.
- You gotta have a ticket.
- Press pass.
- Oh.
- Is the lady going around again too?
- No, thanks. I've had enough.
The safest ride at the fair.
Get tickets now for this ride.
Go and get tickets for this ride.
It is the longest,
fastest thrill ride
at the fairgrounds.
Get tickets now
if you care to ride.
Three rings for a dime. Hurry.
- You feel safer down here?
- Oh!
- I thought you were...
- I changed my mind.
I was standing there
watching you walk away.
Every step you took, your hair bounced
up and down on the back of your neck.
It was really nice. I don't know if
that's what got me, but here I am.
Now it's your turn
to say something.
What can I say? I don't know you.
- I can arrange that.
- And all you know about me
is that my hair bounces
up and down when I walk.
- Everybody's hair bounces up and down.
- Mine doesn't.
I mean, girls.
Well, look over there.
Well, maybe it wasn't your hair. Maybe
it was the way you held your shoulders.
- Walk away again. Let me see.
- All right.
Hey! Hey, wait a minute!
- Where are you going?
- You told me to walk away.
- Yeah, but I...
- Really, I have to go anyway.
- Why?
- Well, I...
Well, what? What are you afraid of?
- I'm not afraid of anything.
- Good.
Then what would be wrong with you
and me sitting down over there
and exchanging our ideas
of life over a Coke?
Nothing wrong. It's just that...
I'm not saying it's a great idea.
I'm just asking what's bad about it.
What could we lose? Let's give it
five minutes. What do you say?
Here we are, two people who
know nothing about each other.
Maybe we should. Maybe it would be
fun to find out what we're like.
- Maybe it'll be dull.
- What do we do if it's dull?
- We break it up.
- How do we do that?
One of us just says, "Let's
break it up." That's the end.
You go east, I go west. No hard
feelings. No questions asked.
- Ag reed?
- Ag reed.
Okay. Here we go.
Hold on! Here we go!
Hearing words
that I have never heard
From a man I've yet to meet
Now, with rolly coasters,
that's different. They're fun.
You oughta see the one in New York.
There's one in Chicago
that's pretty good.
There's one out at
the beach in Los Angeles.
It's not bad, but the one in New York,
the one across the river, that's the one.
- It's got a dip of 200 feet.
- You've been everywhere, haven't you?
Not yet. When I first
started out in this game,
I worked around
on different papers.
But now, I'm afraid the great Des
Moines Register's got me hog-tied.
Someday, I'll work on
a bigger paper though.
I'm sure you will.
Well, I think I'd better go
the rest of the way alone.
I'd have a pretty hard time
explaining you to my folks.
Yeah, I guess you would. Everybody
has a hard time explaining me.
- See you again?
- Well, I...
Or would you like to say,
"Let's break it up"?
Oh, no! Well, I mean, do you?
Look, bobbylocks,
don't worry about me.
Anytime I wanna throw in the
sponge, you'll know it.
I just won't be around.
Well, I don't know what the
family's plans are for tonight.
- I don't know where I'll be.
- I'll find you.
- How?
- I'm a newspaperman.
It's my job to find the right
people at the right time.
You'll be seeing me. So long.
So long.
What's the matter with you?
What's the trouble, Blue Boy?
Ain't you feelin' good?
This ain't like you, son.
- Ain't sick, is he?
- Huh?
Sick? Oh, no, no.
He's in fine shape.
Just had a long trip. Kind of
resting up a bit, that's all.
Oh. I thought he was sick.
Oh, no. He's never
felt better in his life.
You see what a spectacle
you made of yourself?
What are people
gonna say about you?
- Hello, Hank.
- Hello, there.
- What you got this year?
- Never you mind.
She'll put anything you've got
in the shade. You wait and see.
- Come on. Get along, there. Get along.
- Hello, Hank.
Hello, there, Frake. How are ya?
Ah. You got a duroc this time, huh?
- And a good one too. Get in there.
- She's got nice color.
Well, she oughta have.
Her mother before her
was the most beautiful red
sow in the whole world.
- What's her name?
- Esmeralda.
And she'll win the
sweepstakes sure.
Now you look like something.
I don't mind telling you, though,
you had me worried, son,
but I knew you'd come through.
Now you look like a real champion.
- Oh! Excuse me.
- Oh!
Why don't you look where you're goin'?
Gawking around like that,
people'll think you've never
been to a fair before.
I just thought we might meet
somebody we know.
- So what?
- Well, why are you looking around?
Who are you looking for?
I sort of had a half date, with
a guy I met here last year.
- Why don't you keep it?
- What would I do with you?
- Well, look, Wayne...
- I beg your pardon, sir.
- May I trouble you for a match?
- Sure.
- I think I have some right here.
- That's very kind of you.
Okay.
- Here you are. Thanks.
- Why don't you keep them?
- My brother has another pack.
- Sure, sure. Go ahead.
- That's okay.
- Thank you very much.
- You're certainly big with my matches.
- What do you care?
Your pockets are always
full of them.
Look, Wayne, if you really wanna keep your
date with that friend, I wouldn't mind.
- You wouldn't?
- No.
I hardly slept a wink
in that old truck last night.
What I really wanted to do
tonight was to go to bed early
but I didn't wanna disappoint you.
Oh, don't worry about me.
Uh, maybe you'd better.
You do look a little tired.
- And I can get back all right.
- Ah, that's swell, sis.
Thanks. I mean, get
a good rest now.
I will.
Hello.
Take home a beautiful
pennant from the state fair.
Come right over. Help yourself.
Oh, pardon me. I'm looking for
the chief of police's daughter.
- Have you seen her around here anyplace?
- His daughter?
I don't believe I know her.
There's the chief over there.
Why don't you ask him?
Okay. Thank you.
- Good evening, Chief.
- Good evening, son. What can I do for you?
Could you tell me where
your daughter is?
I sort of had a date
to meet her here tonight.
- What?
- Well, it wasn't exactly a date.
She said... I mean, I told her...
Well, let's see.
She's around here somewhere.
Oh, Violet?
Yes, Daddy?
This young gentleman tells me you two
have a date to go out stepping tonight.
Huh?
Well, I guess I must
mean her sister.
I haven't got a sister.
Looks like someone's been
pulling your leg, my boy.
Yeah. That's a pretty good
joke on me, all right.
Well, thanks.
How many, please?
- Huh?
- How many tickets?
Oh. One.
And now for your favorite,
the lovely Emily Edwards,
and That's For Me.
Right
Between the eyes
Quite a belt
That blow I felt this morning
Fate
Gave me no warning
Great
Was my surprise
I saw you standing in the sun
And you were something to see
I know what I like
and I liked what I saw
And I said to myself that's for me
A lovely morning I remarked
And you were quick to agree
You wanted to walk
and I nodded my head
As I breathlessly said
That's for me
I left you standing under stars
The day's adventures are through
There's nothing for me
but the dream in my heart
And the dream in my heart
That's for you
Oh, my darling
- There you are.
- Thank you.
- Who's that singing?
- That's Emily Edwards.
She's kind of cute,
but she's not my type.
She's a redhead.
Now, with brown hair,
that's different.
- Hello, Pat.
- Hi, Pat.
- Hi, girls.
- How are you doin', honey?
- Quiet, you.
- I guess you know a lot of girls, don't you?
Well, in my racket, you know...
For you
- I, uh, just spoke to your father.
- My who?
Your father. You know,
the chief of police.
Oh, that. Didn't you know
I was kidding?
Well, I do now.
And just for that, you're gonna
have to have a drink with me.
When I first saw you up there,
I couldn't believe you were the same girl.
Why not? Was I that bad?
I didn't mean it that way.
You were good, wonderful.
That's just it. A girl singer like
you with Tommy Thomas's band,
I couldn't figure out why you went
to all that trouble today just for me.
- Why shouldn't I? What's wrong with you?
- Oh, nothing wrong with me.
I mean, well, maybe there is,
but don't tell me.
- Like to dance?
- Uh-huh. Do you?
Sure. That's why
I brought it up. Sure.
- We can get our drinks later.
- All right.
The big feature ride of the fair.
Get your tickets for the next ride.
This is the highest, fastest,
safest ride at the fairgrounds.
Get tickets now
for the big, fast ride.
- Come on. I dare you.
- I'm game.
- How many?
- Two, please.
- What you thinking about?
- Why?
Oh, you sort of had
a funny smile on your face.
- You really want to know?
- Uh-huh.
Well, I was just thinking about
you practicing all that time
with your mother's embroidery hoops
just to get even with somebody.
I guess you think I'm kind
of screwy, don't you?
No, I don't. I don't at all.
As a matter of fact,
I like that kind of a fellow.
That's lucky for me, because
I like the kind of a girl
who likes that kind of fellow.
It's a grand night for singing
The moon is flying high
And somewhere a bird
who is bound he'll be heard
ls throwing his heart at the sky
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow
and to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow
and to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love
Maybe it's more than the moon
Maybe it's more than the birds
Maybe it's more
than the sight of the night
In a light too lovely for words
Maybe it's more than the earth
Shiny in silvery blue
Maybe the reason
I'm feeling this way
Has something to do with you
Say, you're pretty good in that
voice department yourself.
I'm an old glee club boy.
The moon is flying high
And somewhere a bird
who is bound he'll be heard
ls throwing his heart at the sky
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow
and to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love
It's a grand night for singing
The moon is flying high
And somewhere a bird
who is bound he'll be heard
Is throwing his heart at the sky
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow
and to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love
And you were something to see
I know what I like
and I liked what I saw
And I said to myself that's for me
A lovely morning I remarked
And you were quick to agree
You wanted to walk
and I nodded my head
As I breathlessly said
That's for me
I left you standing under stars
- The day's adventures are through
- Ow!
There's nothing for me
but the dream in my heart
And the dream in my heart that's
For you
Oh, my darling
That's
For you
Hey, cut that out!
I'll get you for that. You wait
and see now. You just wait.
You two sound like you had
a wonderful time last night.
- Sure did.
- Mmm, terrific.
Wish your father was enjoying himself
instead of brooding over that old pig.
Say, I thought you were going
to bed early last night.
Oh. Well, I was going to,
but I changed my mind.
I went for a ride
on the roller coaster.
- It's much better than it was last year.
- Oh, okay.
I tell you, he's raring to go.
When I left him just now, he was
strutting around prouder than a peacock.
- You'd think he owned the place.
- Thank goodness.
Maybe now you'll
give me a little time.
Yes, sir, he's all right.
Wait till you see him.
There ain't a hog ever was or
ever will be that can touch him.
For what we're about to receive,
O Lord, make us duly thankful. Amen.
- You said grace before, Daddy.
- Yeah.
I did? Well, I'm going to
keep on saying it all day.
I just hope he stays like he
is till the judges see him!
Why, they hardly tasted them!
And I like my sweet pickles best.
They don't have to taste much.
They're experts.
Don't be so jittery, Mother.
- There's that Mrs. Metcalfe.
- Hmm?
- Behind the lady in the red hat.
- Oh, yes, I see her.
So biggety. Why, she was
just lucky last year.
Her pies weren't
half as good as yours.
- Why, hello, Mrs. Metcalfe. Pardon me.
- Hello.
Going to win all the
prizes again this year?
I don't know about all, but I have high
hopes for my pickles and mincemeat.
Same as you.
Look. They like your sour pickles.
This is the last year I'm
ever gonna enter anything.
- It isn't worth it.
- Oh, Mother, you say that every year.
Please.
Thank you.
Well, aren't they going
to announce their decision?
Not until they finish
with the mincemeat.
Thank you.
I don't remember telling you to
cover this part of the fair.
Hello, boss.
Thought you were specializing in human
interest stories on the midway.
What's wrong with putting in a plug
for the housewives of our state?
That, my friend, is Mrs. America.
Do tell. And what dainty
putter-upper
of what delicious preserve is the
cause of your presence here?
Look, forget you're the managing editor of
a newspaper and try to act intelligent.
Have you ever seen me with
the type who's a good cook?
No, but I've seen you
with every other kind.
You had to get around
to these sometime.
Shove off. Let me finish this
story. It's for your paper.
Sure. Only I hope it's better than
the one you turned in last night,
"Fun on a Roller Coaster." Ouch.
Boy, you'd better hope
the old man misses that one
or he'll never give you a
shot at that job in Chicago.
That's yours, isn't it?
Mmm.
Do you think they liked it?
They must have. They
certainly ate enough.
Your attention, please.
Silence, please.
ladies and gentlemen.
Quiet, please!
We are now ready to announce
the awards. Sweet pickles.
First prize to Mrs. Edwin
Metcalfe of Pottsville.
Second prize to...
To Mrs. Agnes Field
of Arcadia.
Sour pickles.
First prize to
Mrs. Melissa Frake of Brunswick.
Oh, Mother.
Second prize to
Mrs. Edwin Metcalfe.
And now, ladies and gentlemen...
Quiet, please. As you know,
we occasionally give a plaque
for distinguished achievement.
As you are doubtlessly aware,
this plaque is only given
in rare cases.
And on this occasion,
my colleagues and I
have voted unanimously
that it be given to a lady who has
concocted the most delicious,
the most succulent
and spiciest mincemeat
ever entered in a state fair.
The lady who wins this distinction
is none other than Mrs.
Melissa Frake of Brunswick.
- Oh, Mother! Oh!
- Congratulations. I'm so glad.
I've got the most a woman
can get in life, Margy.
- If I think any more about it, I'll cry.
- Stand where you are, please.
Hold it. Thank you.
Thank you very much, ladies.
Your picture will appear in the
Register tomorrow morning.
Good day.
- See, Mother? You're famous.
- I'm worn out.
I'm going up to the trailer
and lie down.
I never knew what a strain it was
to get something you really wanted.
- I'll take these, dear.
- Oh, my hat too.
Now you run along
and enjoy yourself.
My horse is number 8,
Tessie In the green shirt.
Come on, Tessie! Come on!
Get up there. Come on!
Attagirl, Tessie.
Pass her! Pass her!
Attagirl, Tess!
Oh, she made it!
She won! She won!
Oh, Pat, your horse won!
it can't be much fun for you
just hanging around waiting
to catch me between songs.
Can't think of anything
I'd rather be doing.
Anyway, we can... I mean, can
we go someplace after the show?
I thought maybe we'd have
something to eat or something.
Well, I can't tonight, Wayne.
- It's Marty's birthday.
- Who's Marty?
The boy I sing with in the band. We're
giving a surprise party for him.
Wouldn't you like to come?
I was kind of counting
on being alone with you.
I know. I'd like that better too.
But this is a party
we cooked up a week ago.
We're giving it in my rooms
at the hotel
- so I can't very well back out now.
- Hey, Emily.
- They're playing the introduction.
- All right, Marty.
Now don't go away.
I'll be right back.
Okay, let's go.
Listen, kids, I got
the greatest number here...
McGee, if you ever scare me
like that again...
I got the greatest number I ever plugged,
and I'm gonna give you first crack at it.
Buzz off, McGee. We're busy.
Eh, just like all singers,
they don't like songs.
- Hi, buddy.
- Hello.
- You in the music business?
- No. I'm a farmer.
A farmer. What a night I'm having.
Well, uh, you're a friend
of Emily's, ain't ya?
That's right.
- My name's McGee.
- My name's Wayne Frake.
- You in the music business?
- Yeah, I'm a song plugger.
- I work on songs till they get popular.
- How do you mean work on 'em?
I thought songs got popular
because people like 'em.
That's naive. How can people like
a song if they don't hear it?
You got to get the big
singers to sing it first.
How do you do that?
There's all kinds of ways,
and none of them is easy.
You got no idea what a snook like me has
to do to get a song on the hit parade.
Last week I fell down in
front of Dinah Shore's taxi
just to get in
conversation with her.
Every Christmas, I got to remember
to send Sinatra a new bow tie.
When a bandleader's
wife has a baby,
I gotta stay home with it
on the nurse's night out.
It's a big question whether Mairzy
Doats would have been a hit
if I hadn't had known
how to change a "didey."
- Is that a new song you got there?
- Yeah, and it's a honey.
A natural for your friend Emily.
You wouldn't wanna help me
get it to her, would ya?
I am not at all niggardly
when it comes to payola.
- Payola?
- Ah, it's a technical term. Forget it.
The man who wrote this song is
starving in an attic in Brooklyn.
His wife ran out on him,
left him penniless with two kids.
She even took the piano with her
so now he can't write no more.
If this song ain't a hit, there's
only one thing left for this man,
the river.
On the other hand, if somebody was to
get a great artist like Emily Edwards
to introduce it with
a band on the radio,
this man's fortune would be made and
his genius preserved for posterity.
How do you know he ain't
another Stephen Foster?
- I don't. Only...
- Just read those words.
Here. Take a couple of copies. I'll hum
the tune so you can see how they fit.
Follow me.
Right there.
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow
and to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love
Maybe it's more than the moon
Maybe it's more than the birds
Maybe it's more
than the sight of the night
In a light too lovely for words
Maybe it's more than the earth
Shiny in silvery blue
Maybe the reason
I'm feeling this way
Has something to do with you
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow
and to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love
La, la, la, la, la, la
- Hey, where's my drink?
- Let's see what else we've got here.
Look, Wayne, how about
your singing a chorus?
No, thanks. You're doing
all right without me.
- But I want them to hear you.
- You can't be as good as she says.
- You'd be surprised. Come on.
- No, really.
Come on. Don't tell me
we have to coax you.
How about singing one
of those corn-fed ditties
you guys sing around
these little towns?
- Come on, Wayne. Sing anything you like.
- Yeah, you can't tell.
You might have something
we can use with the band.
As a matter of fact, if you need a new song,
I've got one right here I like very much.
He didn't expect to sing, but
he brought his music with him.
- Would you like to try it with me?
- You do it yourself.
- Did you write it?
- No, I didn't. A fellow gave it to me.
- Okay, bud.
This ought to be something.
Maybe you'll never be
the love of my life
Maybe I'm not the boy
of your dreams
But isn't it kind of fun
to look in each other's eyes
Swapping romantic gleams
Maybe you're not a girl
to have and to hold
Maybe I'm not a boy who would stay
But isn't it kind of fun
carousing around the town
Dancing the night away
Isn't it kind of fun holding hands
According to a sweet
and corny custom
Isn't it kind of fun making vows
Admitting that we both
intend to bust 'em
Maybe we're out for laughs
A girl and a boy
Kidding across a table for two
But haven't you got a hunch
that this is the real McCoy
And all the things
we tell each other
Are true
I'm not a girl
for sentimental tripe
I never go for the Romeo type
Over a dewy-eyed Juliet
No one has seen me drool yet
I don't say our hearts are tied
By love's eternal tether
But using words less dignified
Isn't it kind of fun to be together
Maybe you'll never be
the love of my life
Maybe I'm not the girl
of your dreams
But isn't it kind of fun
to look in each other's eyes
Swapping romantic gleams
Maybe I'm not a girl
to have and to hold
Well, maybe I'm not
a boy who would stay
But isn't it kind of fun
carousing around the town
Dancing the night away
Oh, isn't it kind
of fun holding hands
According to a sweet
and corny custom
Isn't it kind of fun making vows
Admitting that we both
intend to bust 'em
Maybe we're out for laughs
A girl and a boy
Kidding across a table for two
- But haven't you got a hunch
- That this is the real McCoy
And all the things
we tell each other
Are true
- Wonderful.
- That was great.
You know, you're right about
that song, Wayne. I like it too.
- You do?
- "Billings Publishing Company," huh?
- A guy named McGee give you this?
- That's right.
How much did he slip you
for plugging it tonight?
Wait a minute, Marty!
He didn't slip me anything.
Didn't he promise to come
through with the old payola?
- He used that expression.
- I'll bet he did. That's great, Emily.
Your boyfriend cashing in on you.
- How do you like that?
- Wayne!
Wayne.
Wayne, wait a minute.
I'm sorry, Emily.
I just couldn't help it.
He's been putting in digs
ever since I got here.
I know he was asking for it,
but please don't go.
You don't think I'd cash in on being
friends with you like he said, do you?
Of course not. And he wouldn't have
said it, only he's had a few drinks.
- Please come back.
- It just wouldn't work, Emily.
I'd let him have it the first
time he opened his mouth.
Look. Why don't you
walk around the block?
Give me a chance to get rid
of them. How about that?
I'd hate to have you
break up the party.
I'll tell them I have a headache.
When you come back, we'll be alone.
That's the way
you wanted it, isn't it?
- Okay. How long?
- Come back in half an hour.
Emily, I...
- Half an hour.
- Make it 15 minutes.
All right.
Only a few stars left.
Yeah, and they look kind of tired.
Funny how a day creeps on.
So slowly at first
you think it's never coming.
Then all of a sudden,
it spreads out over the sky,
the sun starts shining.
People loom up like that too.
Are you really gonna go home and
marry that guy you're engaged to?
That's what girls usually do, isn't it?
Marry the men they're engaged to.
Yeah. They're usually
sorry afterward.
Think you'll every marry?
Who, me? Sure. Sometime.
Only trouble is, if I ever found
a girl I cared that much about,
I'd care too much about it to
wish a guy like me off on her.
- Sounds kind of hopeless.
- I guess it is.
It's pretty hard for me
to picture myself,
what do they call it,
popping the question.
Can you imagine me suddenly turning
to some girl and blurting out,
"Will you marry me?"
No. I can see you wouldn't.
Well, bobbylocks, you've
made a very wise decision.
Anyway, I'd be no good
for you, no good at all.
Of course, you'd be
awfully good for me.
Say, what about your old man's hog?
Aren't they gonna judge
him this afternoon?
Oh, yes. I guess
I'd better be going.
- Wayne's probably in already.
- it's getting pretty late.
- Don't you want me to go with you?
- No. It's better if you don't.
- Will I see you tonight?
- In front of the roller coaster?
8:30.
Well, I...
- Good night, honey.
- Good night.
- Pat?
- Yes?
I was only talking. I couldn't
marry anybody but you, ever.
Well, Blue Boy,
this is the great day,
your hour of judgment.
Now take it easy there now.
Don't get your face dirty.
Look, Mother, Blue Boy's already
won. There's his blue ribbon.
Oh, that thing?
That's only the class award.
That means he's won
his class of senior boars.
I'm getting him ready now to go
in for the grand championship.
- Is he all right?
- All right? Why, just look at him.
He's fit as a fiddle.
Class 51, Hampshire senior sows,
- pavilion number two.
- Better go in now, son.
Get seated.
We go in right after this.
- We'd better get going.
- Good luck, Pa.
- Thanks, Ma.
- You too, Blue Boy.
- We'll be pulling for you.
- All right. Bye. See you later.
Well, let's see.
Is your face clean, son?
Yes, you're all right.
You gotta look your best, you know.
You taking her in, Hank?
No, not yet. Just taking her
out to put her on the scale.
Blue Boy, what's the matter, son?
Oh, you think
Esmeralda's gone home.
No, she's just gone
out to be weighed.
Hampshire boars, get ready, please.
That's us, son. Come on. Get up.
Oh, don't act this way.
Esmeralda will be back.
She ain't gonna be judged
until after you win.
Come on, boy. Get up.
You hear that? That's the band.
They're playing for you, son.
You can't lay down on me now.
Oh, come on, fella, please.
Attention, please. Attention.
And now, ladies and
gentlemen, I have the honor
of introducing to you
a man whom you all know,
Congressman James A. Goodheart.
During this great day
of boar judging,
you have seen hundreds
of seemingly perfect boars
eliminated,
leaving only two contestants,
the junior champion
and the senior champion,
both perfect specimens
representing excellence
of breeding.
The judges realize the
importance of their decision,
for the boar
they decide is the better
will be acclaimed
grand champion boar
of this year's state fair.
Introducing the first contestant,
Whirlwind...
number 188.
Winner, junior champion boar.
Owner, Mr. R.C. Martin.
He's awful big, isn't he?
Blue Boy will outpoint him.
And now, for the second contestant,
introducing Blue Boy.
- Where's Dad?
- Yes, now what?
Where is he?
Introducing Blue Boy,
number 1494.
Winning senior champion boar.
Owner, Mr. Abel Frake.
Whoa, Blue Boy.
Whoa, Blue Boy. Whoa, Blue Boy.
They didn't look at him
very long, did they?
They'll be back.
Blue Boy, get up. Get up on your
feet. The judges will see you.
Oh, this is terrible.
He'll lose sure.
Get up, Blue Boy. Blue Boy!
Come on, son. Get up. Son?
What's the matter with him?
Get him up.
- We can't judge him lying down.
- Come on, Blue Boy! Get up, will ya?
Blue Boy, come on!
Blue Boy, come on.
Come on, son. Get up.
Come on, Blue Boy.
Get up, will you?
Come on, Blue Boy. Come on.
Just a little tired, that's all.
Attention, please. Attention.
I have the honor to announce the winner
of this year's grand championship.
Hampshire boar, Blue Boy.
it gives me great pleasure.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I'm so happy!
- Oh, Pa!
- Congratulations, Mr. Frake.
My, my. Whoever wrote this
must be a friend
of the Frake family.
"As Mr. Abel Frake
won the grand award,
"he was watched from the
grandstand by his charming wife,
"and talented and beautiful
daughter Marguerite."
- Come on, Wayne. It's getting late.
- Just a minute.
Say, you look mighty pretty tonight.
Is that a new dress?
- Uh-huh. Do you like it?
- Prettiest girl I ever saw.
Okay, I'm ready.
Not too late now. We wanna get
an early start in the morning.
Might be a little late. It's the
last night. So long, Dad.
- Bye.
- So long.
They look nice together,
don't they?
Hmm? What'd you say?
I said we had two lovely children.
Who said we didn't?
I wish Margy would make
up her mind about Harry.
Why? He won't run away.
He's one of those goody-goody boys.
I don't see anything
wrong with that.
You were a good boy
when I fell in love with you.
That's what you thought.
Well, since you're such a gay dog,
you'd better take me to the
midway tonight for a little fun.
- No, Ma, you're all tired out.
- Who said I was tired?
Say. Here's something interesting.
It's about that judge, the fella
that gave you the plaque.
It says here how he had a kind of seizure
afterwards, delirium tremens sort of.
"While Mr. Hippenstahl
was unconscious,
"he kept murmuring
something about mincemeat.
"Those nearby declared they could
smell brandy on his breath."
You fool.
Now, just for that,
you've got to take me out.
Oh, no, Ma.
I've got that nice
tired-out feeling.
- You and I are going to the fair.
- I've seen the fair.
You've seen the hog pavilion.
Are you going
to get out of that chair?
Now, Ma, I'm up.
Now go on in and change
your clothes. Go on.
I want some excitement.
I can hear 'em calling hogs
in the clear Ioway air
I can sniff the fragrant
whiff of an Ioway rose
You've got Ioway in your heart
I've got Ioway in my hair
I've got Ioway in my ears
and eyes and nose
Oh, I know all I owe
I owe Ioway
I owe Ioway all I owe
and I know why
I am Ioway born and bred
And on Ioway corn I'm fed
Not to mention
her barley, wheat and rye
I owe Ioway for her ham
And her beef and her lamb
And her strawberry jam
And her pie
I owe Ioway more
than I can ever pay
So I think
I'll move to Calif om-i-ay
- What a shame
You'll be good and gosh
darn sorry when you go
- Don't I know
- When you leave your native state
You'll be feeling far from great
You'll be good and gosh
darn sorry when you go
I'm a seed
Of Ioway grain
You're a breeze
That Ioway blew
I'm a drop
Of Ioway rain
You're a drip of Ioway dew
Oh, I know all I owe
I owe Ioway
- I owe Ioway all I owe and I know why
- Ioway
I am Ioway born and bred
And on Ioway corn I'm fed
Not to mention
her barley, wheat and rye
I owe Ioway for her ham
And her beef and her lamb
And her strawberry jam
And her pie
That's right.
I owe Ioway more
than anyone should owe
So I think I'll start
in owing Idaho
All together.
- What a shame
- You'll be crying like a baby when you go
- Don't I know
When I leave my native heath
With my lip between my teeth
I'll be bawling like a booby
when I go
You're a seed
Of Ioway grain
You're a breeze
That Ioway blew
I'm a drop
Of Ioway rain
You're a drip
Of Ioway dew
Oh, I know all I owe
- I owe Ioway
- I owe Ioway all I owe and I know why
I am Ioway born and bred
and on Ioway corn I'm fed
- Not to mention her barley, wheat and rye
- Barley, wheat and rye
I owe Ioway for her ham
And her beef and her lamb
- And her strawberry jam and her pie
- Pie, pie, pie, pie
- I owe Ioway more than anyone should owe
- Oh
So I think I'll start
in owing Idaho
Better stay
You'll be good and gosh
darn sorry if you go
Don't I know
When you leave your native state
You'll be feeling far from great
You'll be good and gosh
darn sorry when you go
I owe Ioway for her ham
and her beef and her lamb
And her strawberry jam and her pie
I owe Ioway more
than I can ever pay
So I think I'll move
to Californ-i-ay
I-O-W! I-O-W! I-O-W! I-O-W-A!
Hooray! Ioway! Yea!
What do you think of this
imitation champagne, Ma?
First time I ever tried it,
and I love it.
It's as good as that
French champagne any day.
- Did you ever taste French champagne?
- No.
Who's that little runt?
- Hmm?
- What's he grinning at?
That's Mr. Hippenstahl,
the pickle and mincemeat judge.
Oh. Oh!
Well, that explains it. He's drunk!
- Quiet, Pa.
- Come on, Ma.
- Let's get out on the midway.
- All right.
Hey, buddy! I wanna thank you for the
plug you gave that song last night.
It's all set with Tommy Thomas for Emily
to sing it in Chicago tomorrow night.
- Chicago?
- Yeah. That's their next date,
the Palmer House.
I'm going with them
on the plane tonight.
Sticking close so they
won't change their mind.
Emily didn't say she was... I didn't
figure on them leaving tonight.
Sure, right after the show.
I wish she'd hurry up and get
out here. I wanna talk to her.
Kind of went overboard for
each other, didn't you, kid?
- Kind of.
- She told me.
Oh, they all tell me everything.
- You going back to the farm soon?
- Tomorrow.
That'll be good.
Come in.
- Oh, hello.
- I was just on my way out.
- I'll say you are. Where's your suitcase?
- Suitcase? What for?
The old man just phoned from Chicago.
He's gonna give you a crack at that job.
- The Eastern syndicate?
- That's right. A column of your own.
- I can't believe it.
- He's leaving for the coast in the morning
and he wants you to fly up to
Chicago and talk to him tonight.
- That means the 8:30 plane.
- How much time have I got?
Practically none. I'm holding a taxi
downstairs. I'll get your shaving things.
- Hey, wait!
- What's the matter?
I can't leave now. I've got a girl
waiting for me out at the fair.
- What'll I do?
- Do? Get another girl in Chicago.
A girl waiting at the fair.
I break my neck getting this chance for you
and you start yapping about some girl.
- This is different. This is not just a girl.
- I know. She's wonderful.
Only girl in the world. And I
suppose this job is just a job.
The kind that comes up every day.
Look, I wanna make something
very clear to you, sonny-boy.
The old man is funny.
When he wants you someplace,
you better, or you're through.
- I know that, but...
- Do you want this job or don't you?
You've got about two minutes
to make up your mind.
Thank you very much.
- What did she say?
- She sees a lot of money coming my way.
- Good. I can use some.
- I don't think it'll do you much good.
She says I'm going
to marry three times.
There they are, folks,
the eight fugitives
from the Follies.
They did a little dance in New York,
but the police commissioner objected.
He demanded that they take
certain things out of the dance.
Understand? Well, rather than
do the emasculated version,
they come out here to give you the
original dance with nothing cut out.
Just to prove to you what you're
gonna see on the inside...
Okay, Mike, let her rip!
- Do you want to go in?
- Huh?
It means nothing to me,
but if you'd like to see it,
I'd be glad to take you in, hmm?
Hmm?
What do you think?
Of course, like I say,
it means nothing to me
unless you wanna go in.
You do? Come on.
Two, please.
- Enjoying yourself?
- Yes, we are.
That's good.
What's that old buzzard
doing, following you around?
Don't be foolish, Abel. He's seeing
the fair, having fun, same as we are.
All aboard. Train now leaving.
Get tickets for this ride.
Another train coming in.
Get your tickets for that high,
fast ride through the sky,
on the big roller coaster
the big feature ride of the fair.
But last night and all the things
we said, was that just kidding?
No, Wayne, it wasn't just kidding.
Well, it certainly wasn't with me.
I thought that...
Oh, what's the difference
what I thought?
But, Wayne, darling, I thought
you understood that...
Well, after all, we were just
two people who met at a fair...
And fell in love, didn't we?
Well, that was something
I hadn't bargained for.
Wayne, will you believe something?
Just one thing.
It's every bit as hard for me
to give you up as it is for...
Well, then why do it?
Why give each other up?
Why don't you come with me,
meet my father and mother
and go home with us tomorrow?
- Because I can't, Wayne. I...
- Hey, Emily.
- You ready?
- No, she isn't!
I'll be right in, Marty.
Wait here, Wayne.
I have to tell you something,
something I should have
told you before,
and I would have, if I
hadn't been such a coward.
Please, wait, Wayne. Please.
You mind if I say something?
- Such as what?
- First, let me get something straight.
When you said that about
taking Emily home with you,
did you mean the works,
a wedding ring and all?
That's it, the works. And
that's the way it's gonna be.
Look, I'll give it to you quick.
She's married.
She's got a husband, see?
He don't work at it very hard.
They split up about a year ago.
He claims he's a songwriter,
but he's just no good at it.
As a matter of fact,
he's just no good, period.
She liked him, though. Sort of
knocked her out for a while.
Come to think of it, you're the first
guy she's looked at since then.
I guess I just don't understand
the people in your business.
Take my word, they're the
same as anybody else.
They make mistakes, sure,
but don't everybody?
Are all the people
in your town perfect?
Why didn't she tell me?
She told you why.
She didn't want
to spoil everything.
Maybe she figured she had a right
to a little happiness too.
You know what you and me
need right now?
A drink.
How about it, buddy?
Ring the old pipe!
There she goes. 47! He's
getting higher and higher!
48! Who's next?
Not bad. Not bad at all, Mr. Frake.
Not bad, huh? Thank you.
But you didn't ring the bell,
though. Ho, ho, ho.
I know I didn't ring the
bell, though. Ho, ho, ho.
- Who can? Can you?
- I don't know. I never tried.
- Why don't you?
- I don't know, but I will.
Step right up, neighbor.
Step right up.
- It's kind of heavy, isn't it?
- Allow me.
Thank you.
Now, I suppose the idea is
to lean your weight on it.
Yes. Put all your 120 pounds in it.
Come on, Ma. I'm tired.
Let's go home.
I suppose it's too late to stop
someplace for a cup of coffee.
Who said it was too late?
- Easy does it, pal. Easy does it.
- I'm okay.
Sure, you are.
What about this Eleanor,
the girl from back home?
You say you graduated
from school together, huh?
Yep. She's a fine girl too.
What does she look like, redhead?
- Nope. Blond.
- Oh. I like the redheads.
There's a redhead
lives on the floor below me.
What a dish! I keep thinking,
I'll get off the elevator at the
wrong floor, but I never do.
Why not? Why don't you?
And have my wife make
a cripple out of me for life?
One shoe off,
and the other shoe off.
Diddle, diddle, dumpling
my son John
Hey, that don't rhyme
like it used to.
Did I ever tell you about Eleanor?
She's a girl I went to school with.
- Yes. I know. I know.
- Wonderful!
Just the girl for you.
Wonderful girl.
Look, bobbylocks,
don't worry about me.
Anytime I want to throw in the sponge,
you'll know it. I just won't be around.
- You about ready?
- Yes. See you next year.
Yes, indeed. We'll be here.
Take good care of yourself.
We will.
All right, son, get aboard.
- Bye!
I can't remember when
I've been as tired.
It's that resting
you did at the fair, Ma.
Three days' rest
will tire anybody out.
- Good-bye, Hank!
- Good-bye, Frake! See you next year.
You bet.
For goodness sake,
what's the matter, Margy?
You're crying like there was
never gonna be another fair.
We'll be back next year.
- I never want to see another fair.
- You can say that again.
You meet a lot of people
who play you for a sucker
and have some laughs
at your expense.
When the fair's over, what?
Just chalk it up to
experience, I guess.
Sure, that's why you go
to a fair, experience.
Something new, different.
Yes, sir, the Frakes are
coming home in grand style.
You got your plaque,
I got the grand award,
we're all well and happy, and
Dave Miller owes me five bucks.
There you are. That's Melissa's
plaque for mincemeat.
And this is mine. First prize
for the best boar in the state.
So, you see, Gloomy Gus,
you lost your bet.
Nobody got sick and nothing
bad happened to any of us.
Only thing is, something might have
happened we don't know about.
None of that now.
Come across. $5.00.
- Lemonade, Mr. Miller?
- Yes!
Thank you, Mrs. Frake.
Believe I will.
Would have done your heart good
to hear 'em in church this morning.
Everybody talking about the Frakes
and all the prizes you won.
Well, that's nice.
See you later. I won't
be home for dinner.
- All right, son.
- Where are you going?
Oh, just for a little drive.
Did Wayne have a good time?
He looks a little down.
Had the time of his life,
far as I can make out.
Mr. Miller. Abel?
No, not now, Ma.
Headache better, dear?
How about you, Margy?
Did you have
a good time at the fair?
Answer that, Margy.
It's probably Harry for you.
Well, go on, dear.
Don't let it ring all day.
- Well?
- Let's not be hasty about this now.
Hello?
Doesn't anybody ever answer
the telephone at your house?
Pat! Oh, Pat!
Here? In Brunswick?
Oh, yes. Yes, I do. I do, Pat!
That's all I wanna know. 'Cause
you're going back to Chicago with me.
You're gonna be the wife
of a columnist.
Yeah. How do I drive
out to your place?
Where are you now? Is your car pointed
toward the hotel or the Elk's hall?
Well, get in and keep it
going in that direction.
Just keep going until you see me.
Oh, yes, and hurry!
Hurry! Hurry.
Margy, you didn't
answer my question.
Did you have
a good time at the fair?
Oh, yes, Mr. Miller! It was the most
wonderful fair in the whole world!
There!
You see? What did I tell you?
Margy! Margy!
That's Mr. Miller's car!
Well!
She'll be right back, I'm sure.
$5.00.
Oh, Pat!
Hi!
It's a grand night for singing
The stars are bright above
The earth is aglow and
to add to the show
I think I am falling in love
Falling
Falling in love