Newspaper.
- Is it true?
- Look yourself, sir.
"Following the success of our U-boats it has been decided ..."
So now we know, sir.
Reception!
- ... I want a room
- A room for my wife and myself.
Sorry, we are full.
- But we just got married.
- He has to join the ship tomorrow!
29, but I might turn you out.
Register first!
¿Captain Hardt?
You'll need a diving suit. He is still at sea.
- The U29 moored an hour ago, sir.
- Who would be a U-boat captain?
- A letter arrives, send it to my room.
- Very good.
- Capt Rigg wants another manicure, room 46.
- I know...
Well?
Captain Hardt is to report to headquarters immediately.
- He hasn't arrived yet.
- What's his room number?
- 54
- Have you seen him?
Not for 16 days.
- You know him by sight?
- No.
Well, try the Turkish baths at Koernische.
Koernische Strasse ...
- Hullo; kept my room?
- 54, Captain Hardt.
- Cigarettes?
- Sorry, Capt. We're sold out.
- Again?
- Got yet tobacco.
And a beautiful pipe. Only six marks.
Nothing doing it. I never smoke a pipe.
- C'mon, lets bath and shape the body.
- Did you sink any food ships?
- Four.
- Makes me hungry just to think of it.
16 days without a smoke.
- This is absolutely ...
- Perfect!
Food first. A cigar is best after dinner.
You're always right, sir.
Back again, Captain. Congratulations.
- A table for two?
- And a meal for ten.
I put in the out booth. They've just gone.
- Felix, darling!
- After dinner, Schatzchen.
Listen Hans: We've been 16 days in a submarine.
It makes 48 tins of sardines, 768 beastly little fishes.
- I could eat a horse.
- He probably did.
Sorry, it's a meatless day.
We'll have roast goose with foie gras,
- Apple pie, plum pudding.
- Big as a depth charge.
Gentlemen... please!
- Here is the menu.
- Thank you.
- Is it a joke?
- Boiled fish!
- Carrots, beets, potatoes.
- No potatoes, sir!
- Bring a pail of bread and butter.
- No butter. Margarine tomorrow perhaps.
We sank the finest food in the world
Then turn to port and you give us ...
- Boiled fish and carrots!
- I agree...
Fifth floor.
Captain Hardt? Message from
headquarters. Report immediately.
- Carry on as she goes, quartermaster.
- As she goes, sir.
What an idea, putting a
motorbike in a submarine!
11:15, sir.
- 11:14.
- Can at least open the kit pack?
11:15, sir.
11:15, gentlemen.
What it says about the motorbike, sir?
- What you got there?
- A chart of the mine defences.
And a photograph of the Old Man of Hoy;
it seems to be a rendez-vous.
3* 25'. It's off my chart.
- It's in mine.
- Here.
Gentlemen, we are on a special mission.
Our orders are to proceed to
Scapa Flow in the Orkney Islands.
It's a big job and a dangerous one.
I know I can count on you.
That's all. Thank you.
Hartman, full speed ahead.
- 3-2-0.
- 3-2-0, sir.
- Schuster?
- Yes, sir.
"Your" motorbike, it'll take me to Longhope,
in the island of Hoy, base
of the British Grand Fleet.
"Once across the minefield,
spend the night at the Man of Hoy."
Lt. Schuster will take over
and wait for your return.
You will proceed to the Longhope School
where you will report to our agent...
Fraulein Thiel. "
A woman? How is she?
- Tall, dark, 21...
- My type, sir!
- Have a shave, sir.
- See what's in the kit pack.
- I still do not see why a motorcycle.
- Schuster ...
A man landed from a submarine
would not travel by motorbike.
- Ah, camouflage!
- Ah, camouflage.
A well-worn tweed, the thing for Scotland.
Too big for me; fits you all right.
This suit's mine! I bought it in Berlin.
"Temple & Conway, Saville Row, London"
"Ernest H-A-R-T"
Your name, sir, spelled in the English way.
Clever. Stole my own suit.
Trying to make a spy of me.
This Fraulein Thiel; is there
a photograph of her?
- How would they get her into the school?
- That's their business.
Miss Anne, dear, it is nearly four.
- The carrier will be here.
- Coming!
Look out!
- My poor paint...
- The handle broke.
Oh, there's nothing hurt.
Nanny dear, I've loved my holiday, every minute.
How couldn't I know to look after your?
I have plenty of practice.
Don't stand there smiling, fix a label.
I thought you might like to have this.
You dropped your passport, Miss Butter Fingers.
- It's a photo of John and me.
- And you give it to me?
- I have lots more. They printed thousands.
- Beautiful!
"Rvd. John Harris, vicar of St. Swithin's,"
"and his fiancee, Miss Anne Burnett,"
"who was appointed to the
school at Orkney Islands..."
- You'll miss him, deary.
- Oh, he's going come see
me when he got a leave.
A car has stopped at the gate!
Would it be too much to ask for some tea?
It suits me, but you'll have to wait until
this lady is under way. Maggie, the bag.
- We're waiting for the carrier.
- To take the train to Thurston. Excuse me a minute.
- Are you going up north?
- To the Orkney Islands.
- Where the fleet is, right?
- Got a job there. I'm a teacher.
- It's four o'clock!
- My train leaves at five!
How strange Sandy Ross being late.
- Sandy Ross?
- Have you seen him?
We saw an old car with his name.
He seemed to be broken down.
- Where?
- About 8 km.
- God!
- Can't catch another train?
Missing the boat would mean losing a whole day!
Tell Mr. McLeod! We'll take the hearse.
No. Wait.
- I can run you to the station.
- It would be lovely.
- What about your tea?
- It doesn't matter.
- The Providence sent you.
- Come along.
Maggie, put her things in the car!
We're taking her to Dingwall.
Be sure to keep warm. She's easy to catch a cold!
You're a blessing in disguise.
Hold your dear passport. Don't forget your woolies.
- It's terribly cold out there.
- I'll take care.
- Never thought you were a teacher.
- But I am.
- I got my degree from Bristol U.
- Then again...
Had to do something after my father died. No money.
- What was your father?
- He was an architect, but not very lucky.
He only had a good job; a tavern in Chester.
And he didn't like it because he was a teetotaler.
- You lived in Chester?
- Yes, on Putnam Street.
- The Orkney Islands; do you have friends there?
- None.
- But John will come to see me.
- Who is John?
My fiance. Want to see a photograph?
Very much.
He is quite good looking.
Orkney Islands; I thought it was
impossible for civilians to go there.
It is. It was a fuzz getting my passport.
- But you got it?
- Yes, here it is.
Complete with photograph. Isn't it terrible?
- Passport photographs are never flattering.
- Haven't you taken the wrong road?
- ¿Is this the route to Dingwall, Edwards?
- Yes, madam.
It probably is a shortcut.
- Are you sure you aren't cold?
- No, I love it.
Remember what your nanny said.
Give Miss Burnett the shetland scarf.
- Really I don't want it.
- No, you mustn't catch cold.
- Done?
- All is in order.
Well, hold on tight.
Put on these clothes.
- Did you see a light?
- Where? No.
- I think I heard a splash.
- Take over.
A seagull.
Right, madam. We know you.
- ¿Miss Anne Burnett?
- Yes.
- Schoolteacher?
- This picture, it doesn't really do you justice.
- I tought it as good as my other passport photos.
- Destination?
- Longhope.
- Age?
- 21.
- Married or single?
- Engaged.
- Pass...
- Thank you.
- What about tea, Miss?
- Yes, please.
- What time we get to Longhope?
- In about an hour, Miss.
- You're only passenger 'cept for a telephone linesman.
- Thank you.
Fix your pass there.
- Are you in the wire patrol?
- What do you think?
- Six?
- Six.
I'll pass you.
- Fine passage, James?
- You think so, Walter?
For you. All you do is stand on the bridge, but me?
It is a miracle that I keep this old tub coming.
When will we be in port to see them?
- I'll see about that.
- I hope so.
- You're the new teacher?
- Yes.
It'll be a nice change from the last one.
She was called "Wall Eyed Maggie".
- You got a pass?
- Yes.
I'm a special constable, you understand?
See that? "Orkney Constabulary", for the duration.
No one's up or down without me knowing.
- Miss Anne Burnett?
- Yes.
I'll pass you.
Bob Bratt. Come; there's a minister
and his wife who want to meet you.
- Thank you.
- I'll take it.
- Shut that door!
- All right, Pier Master!
This is Rvd. Hector Matthews. My wife.
- How kind to meet me.
- Welcome to Longhope.
We were thinking, you may prefer a room with us
- To living up at the school house.
- That's very kind, but ...
We thought it'd be highly improper
for so young a girl to be on her own.
- I'm accustomed to look after myself.
- Mrs Matthews is a pretty housekeeper.
- You'll find the charge is very reasonable.
- I'm sure of that.
Shall we discuss it some other time?
Good bye.
- Good bye.
- I'll put you on your road, Miss Burnett.
- Shut that door!
- All right, Pier Master!
- 50 feet.
- Pump up 4 auxiliary.
Pump up 4 auxiliary!
- Dead slow.
- Dead slow, sir.
Stop the pump. Shut 4 auxiliary.
Stop the pump, shut 4 auxiliary!
- 80 feet!
- Flood fives.
Flood fives!
Hold at 80 feet.
Hot? Funny how cold makes you steam.
- We have scraped something, have you heard?
- You would have heard if we had.
Well, gentlemen, I think we are through.
Whoever got the chart of the mine
field deserves the Iron Cross.
Yes, we shouldn't have even
a wood one without it.
Stop motors.
Stopped boat, sir!
Can you hear anything?
No, sir. Nothing.
- Good. I'm going up. 30 feet.
- 30 feet, sir!
Up periscope.
- Stand by to surface.
- Stand by to surface!
- Main vents shut, sir!
- Blow ones.
- Blow twos and threes.
- Blow twos and threes!
25...
20...
- 15 ...
- Stop blowing. Exit stations!
- We review the details?
- Do you think I'll forget?
To be sure. Ready? On top of the cliff?
- Northeast, surrounding rocks.
- Then?
Follow telegraph poles. Rough road.
- 3 miles?
- Right.
At the fork, turn left.
- In the cairn?
- Stop and look for the sign W-NW.
- The woman?
- Fraulein Thiel.
- Motorcycle is asshore, sir.
- Password?
I do not know what spell makes me so sad...
- What are you smiling at?
- You sir, saying that in the dark to a woman.
If you are so funny, keep it. Come on.
Come up at same time next 3 nights.
Yes, sir.
- Got everything you want?
- Yes.
- Glasses? ¿Gun?
- All.
Good luck.
Who goes there?
- Constable Bob Bratt.
- Pass.
Quiet tonight.
Hi there!
Put that light out!
- Is somebody calling?
- What you think you're doing showing a naked light?
- I'm very sorry.
- Put it out!
Yes.
- Haven't you read the regulations?
- No.
- All the worse. And you're a teacher!
- It's you, Mr. Bratt? I'm very sorry.
Well, that's all right, Miss.
I'm single handed and the fleet here, I have to keep an eye.
A spy would give his head to get here,
but he won't get by Bob Bratt.
- Good night.
I do not know what spell makes me so sad.
An ancient legend duped me and not let me.
- What was the patrol doing?
- They saw the light.
- You're alone?
- Of course.
- Where this door leads?
- To the kitchen.
- Does the ladder?
- A room.
Butter!
You gave me a fright.
So you are Fraulein Thiel.
Yes, captain Hardt.
- From now on please speak in English.
- And eat in English?
- Come in.
- Thank you.
- How did you get here?
- A demure look and a fake passport.
You speak English like a native.
I shouldn't go very far. I am the teacher.
- Teacher!
- My name is Anne Burnett.
- Please call me that.
- Anne Burnett.
Are you mad? Wearing an uniform here?
If I'm shot, it will be as an officer, not a spy.
Being a civilian I have no such defenses.
I beg your pardon.
A whole ham, white bread... and butter.
- Butter!
- Butter.
These English are not feeling the pinch.
I had no idea secret agent's was such a comfortable profession.
It has its uncomfortable moments.
Talking about it, school opens the day after tomorrow.
- I wonder how I should get on.
- So do I.
In Germany girls no longer wear silk stockings.
I'll show you your room. It's upstairs.
- I haven't yet been told what I'm to do here.
- You'll be told tomorrow.
Not tomorrow. Now!
What are your orders?
- I beg your pardon?
- Your orders, Captain Hardt!
To report for duty to Fraulein Thiel and obey her orders.
Exactly! Pick up your motorbike and go to bed.
- Do I take it to bed with me?
- Suit yourself. There's a parking space at the wash den.
Sorry.
Good night.
Hey, hey! Why are you locking me in?
- A woman comes to clean in the morning.
- I can lock my own door.
I think this is safer.
- May I come in?
- Come in.
- Good morning.
Your breakfast is in my room.
There's a beautiful view from my window.
I didn't come here for holidays. I have more
important things to do than admire the view.
All right!
Well... ¿The plan?
To sink 15 of these ships.
How?
He will tell you.
Who is he?
A British officer with a grudge.
He was in command of a destroyer.
- He lost it in a collision.
- How?
A wrong order. He'd been drinking.
Traitor and drunkard, an honor for the British navy.
- Where did this happen?
- Off Cyprus.
- HMS Connaught. February 16.
- Then you knew?
- Of course. Commander Ashington.
- Lieutenant. He was dismissed of the ship.
- Where did you meet him?
- At Leith, a month ago.
- And found he had a price.
- Rather a high one.
- Paid by whom?
- Germany.
Only by Germany?
And me.
I suppose we should have to meet.
Come down in a minute.
Captain Hardt.
Suppose we'll sit down and get acquainted.
- Give him a drink; loosen him up a bit.
- I'd rather get to business.
Drink when you can in this job. That's my motto.
May we confine on what rests before us.
All alike, you Germans, one tech mind.
Draw the curtains, get the charts. Let's go.
Here we are. Three years we've been sitting on our bottoms in Keith.
- Met in Jutland.
- That's why you haven't put it out a notice since.
- You mean ...
- All right, we both won.
Point is: with the fleet around the corner,
and that the large fleet in Scapa watching,
- You couldn't get to the Irish Channel...
- I know that. What's your plan?
Two cruisers squadrons will sweep southward.
I know that too. It is routine.
But wouldn't you give an eye to know when, where & how?
- Do you know?
- Everything except the actual time, and I'll get it.
- Which squads?
- The 1st and 5th.
And the course?
Here it is, pencil line. East of Swona.
If we got submarines to rendez-vous...
- In Sandwick Bay.
- In Sandwick Bay,
- We could bag the lot,
- Exactly.
They may alter the course, but I'll find out.
- From whom?
- My brother. He is flag captain.
- He too...?
- No. It's a case of brotherly trust.
When will this movement take place?
Tomorrow. Next day. Anytime.
But you'll get plenty of notice.
We can't take submarines off blockade duty on suppositions.
Supposition nothing! Those squadrons are going to sail.
- The date?
- I'll get it.
It would be the biggest smash of the war.
Then, we understand each other?
I hope so.
- To our next meeting.
Mind you, behave yourself.
- Mr Ashington, what is your ship?
- The old Warspite.
She won't be going out with the squad?
- She's laid out for repairs, as usual.
- Pity.
You see, children. When look at this
little island of ours, you realize it is...
... the protector of much larger countries and continents.
I know you don't like it but this isn't for a German audience.
- You've almost persuade me to become British.
- What would I say next?
There's the bit about the empire where the sun never sets.
But it needs explain.
Which way it goes? West-East or East-West?
It worries me. I bet children will know.
I shouldn't worry. You can teach them more important things.
How to get to an island guarded like Gibraltar.
How to twist British and German
officers round your little finger.
Lots of things never taught in school.
Doesn't all that belong to evening school for grown-ups?
It is evening, and I am a grown-up.
But you're not one of my pupils.
Tell me: what became of the real Miss Burnett?
- You know "Red Riding Hood"?
- It had a happy ending...
That's why this story is different.
- She met with an accident?
- Yes, an accident.
- Were you present?
- I obey orders in my service.
What a service!
Have you ever fire a torpedo on an unarmed ship?
- That's different!
- It's certainly more of the same.
Why do you look down on me?
I obey orders, as you obey yours.
We don't choose the jobs we do.
We are parts of a machine of destruction. Like it or not.
Where is the key?
Here.
Good night.
Thank you, children. That's very nice.
Now you may dismiss.
- Thank you very much. Good day.
- Good day.
- Any news?
- I got it. They sail tomorrow.
- What time?
- 7:00 a.m.
- No changes?
- No changes.
- You get in touch with your ship tonight.
- Be ready to leave at ten o'clock.
- Tonight?
- Of course. Good work.
- What is all this?
- Fraulein Thiel leaves with me.
- This is the Reverend Hector Mathews.
- Is it? I mean, how'd you do?
I'm sorry I can't shake hands. My name's
John Harris. I'm looking for the school.
- To what purpose, may I ask?
- See my fiancee, Ms. Burnett.
Ms Burnett didn't tell me she had any
connection with an English character.
No; but she soon will have.
If you are going to stay on the island
you may have a room at my house.
- Far cheaper than lodging at the post office.
- Would it? I mean, that's very kind.
- May bring your fiancee to dinner tonight.
- Well...
If you give me your meat coupons, we will make a roast.
- They're in my inside pocket and I rather...
- Allow me.
At 7:30 sharp.
- You wanted her to remain...
-  Who cares what I want? Don't you see...
- I only see one thing: my orders.
- Where are they?
- Here.
- What do you mean here?
What were the actual orders?
On completion of the mission you'll be taken on board.
- On completion?
- Yes, on completion.
And, is it completed?
Until your submarines come up with
our squadrons the job hasn't even began.
- I think he's right.
- No other way of looking at it.
I shall leave with a message. And tell Schuster
to depart tomorrow night for both of us.
Now you're talking sense.
- Who's that?
- Turn off the light.
I'm awfully sorry. There must be another room.
Come on in.
Thank you. Not expect to see officers staying here.
- It is difficult to find accomodation.
- Right.
- We were just gonna have tea.
- Join us.
Oh no really; I came to find my fiancee, Miss Burnett.
- Is she here?
- Milk and sugar?
- Very kind.
- Let me take it.
More than kind of you. It's rather heavy.
- How'd you do?
- Sit down.
Thank you.
Wasn't strange of me not letting
her know that I'd arrive?
- Your tea.
- Thank you.
Well, I should give her a shout.
I'm averse to shouting. All of us here.
Well, in that case...
She'll be surprised to find me here, won't she?
- Cake?
- No, thank you.
I brought this gramophone, and heaps of new records.
Have you heard "The Soldier's March"?
It's rather large, but it has a beautiful tune.
I don't recognize that metal ribbon.
- What is it?
- The Iron Cross, second class.
Second class... Then you must be a prisoner of war.
No. You are.
Oh dear!
Oh, they haven't arrived yet!
During a war, lateness for a meal is not only incivility but criminal waste.
- I'm scare the meat will burn.
- I bring it nonetheless.
I will not wait longer.
I'm greatly disappointed on Rev. Harris.
For what we are to receive may the
Lord make us truly thankful. Amen.
- Don't bite these, are macaroni.
- I should have some expla...
- Better wait here for them to come.
- Why?
- 'Stay here!
- Hurry.
- Who is it?
- Rev. Matthews and his wife.
Excuse me.
- Good evening my dear.
- You chose a high night to play calls.
Obligations to society take precedence over nature.
- That's rather a compliment.
- A compliment was not my intention. We waited an hour.
- Outside?
- At table.
- At table?
- Precisely.
- He's upset about the meat.
- Our concern has nothing to do with material.
If you and Rev. could not come, courtesy demands a message.
- Then were you expecting us?
- You must have received our invitation.
- I'm afraid not. I had no idea.
- I find hard to believe he failed to convey it.
- I'm afraid he did.
- That's odd.
If I were your fiance, to see you after so long,
- ... I would forget everything else.
- Perhaps you would explain...
- The minute he arrived, he had a nasty attack.
- Attack?
Yes, sort of a suffocation. He wasn't able to say anything.
Oh, he is ill? I'm greatly relieved.
I put a room at his disposal. I
couldn't understand his not coming.
He's gone to bed an hour ago.
- It is the most sensible.
- An embarrassing situation.
Ms. Matthews should stay tonight.
- Shall I?
- There's no need for that.
As a Minister, I say that your position ...
- As a future wife?
- People might talk.
In wartime? Do not worry about me.
My conscience calls me talk to Rvd. Harris.
I will not disturb him to satisfy anybody's conscience.
Good night.
Then...  You choose to defy me?
Not at all. But this is my house I please myself.
We'll see what the Education Committee thinks of it.
- Good night.
I understand, but he'll be fighting his conscience all night.
Sandwick Bay? What a hole!
- Should take 2 hs to rendez vous.
- I hope so.
We are 15 submarines. Our orders
are not to waste a single torpedo.
- Good.
- We could sink a few.
Tomorrow at same time come and pick us up.
Yes, sir. Bad luck missing a fight like this
- for a woman.
- Mind your own business.
- Good luck!
- Thank you, sir.
- Schuster!
- Sir?
I nearly forgot.
- What is it?
- Butter.
- Sorry...
- Come on.
- What happened? Did the message go?
- On its way.
Never been so cold. Must be out of shape.
Damn fellow left me sitting in the hail.
Is not our costume to entertain enemy officers
however useful they may have been.
- How does it feel to make history?
- I'll make some coffee to keep us warm.
Don't you keep him up; it's been a
strenous evening, time he went to bed.
Still you have some way to go,
suppose you set us an example?
Come on, have a bit of tact: can't
you see we want to be together?
It's only two hours to dawn. Somebody
may wonder what has become of you.
- I think I'll have another drink.
- Yes, do.
After all you'll have the whole
day tomorrow to bid you adieu.
Good night.
- Persuasive fellow, aren't you?
- Sleep well.
That's better.
- You didn't give him much choice.
- Oh, he's quite happy.
He has his whiskey and he is swinging down
the lane, convinced you're in love with him.
In a minute I'll be swinging up to bed.
No, no. I want to talk to you. And want that coffee.
It's 4:00. Let's talk tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Can't you see this chance will never come again?
Our job is done.
In one hour the submarines will be
meeting and in two they should strike.
And in a week, you and I will be in Kiel,
How we'll celebrate!
Then on to Berlin. I can see us lunching at the Hotel Adlon.
You'll have the Iron Cross in your bag
and you'll be the only girl in Berlin...
in silk stockings.
Silk stockings I might take to bed.
I have served under many commanders
but none I admired more than you.
- What will you do when you're home again?
- You just told me.
- Trip to Berlin, the Adlon Hotel.
- And after Berlin?
Another job. Another island. Another Ashington.
And another captain Hardt?
Perhaps. Please let me go.
Commander Thiel, don't forget that you won a victory.
A good commander must celebrate with his men.
If I'm in command, I order you to let me go.
David.
Jill.
- These have been the worst 10 minutes I ever spent.
- Me too.
- It's all over now.
- Yes, darling.
Little fool, what you mean coming out here without a coat?
Running risks like that?
- Where is he?
- Upstairs, locked in his room.
You are a marvel.
Sir!
Special Constable Bob Pratt, sir.
- Know who I am?
- You're Commander Blacklock, sir.
When the patrol arrives tell them
to stand by. Nobody goes in or out.
- Where is your armlet?
- When I heard German spies are about
I put it in my pocket, to be close and not recognized.
- Keep your eyes skinned.
- Aye, Aye, sir.
David, you won't have him arrested
until I leave the house, will you?
Give us credit for a little imagination.
Besides, he's safe enough in here.
Couldn't you let him go back to his ship
and at least give him a fighting chance?
Too risky. He might find someone who
knew the real Thiel and Ashington.
- You hear that?
- What is it?
The destroyer's flotilla.
They've been loading extra depth charges all
night. The result of our midnight labours.
In a few hours, there won't be
any U-boats in Sandwick Bay,
just a few spots of grease,
drifting out to the North Sea.
- I think I'm rather sick.
- Here.
Give it a pull a bit.
Woman: you're going into history!
I know.
Buzz upstairs and get your things.
I'm taking you straight to the St. Magnus,
she sails in an hour.
I haven't got anything of my own.
Everything is Anne Burnett's.
Then, here we go.
- I'll be back in half an hour to get him. Stand by.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Sir; you wouldn't like us to save you the trouble?
No. I have personal reasons
for doing this job myself.
You'll look after her?
I'll be on the bridge. So my
cabin is for the lady to use.
- Very kind of yours.
- It's a wee bit little, but it's warm,
- and you can have it all for yourself.
- Thank you.
Well ...
Walter, hear, Walter. I warn you:
Unless I got a day in port to work
on the bottom, it won't last one week.
- We'll see about it, James.
- I hope so.
Excuse me.
The Pastor! I left him tied up in school.
- Poor Mr Harris.
- To the rescue! Good bye.
- You will take care, won't you?
- Indeed.
- All present and correct.
- Thanks.
- Two around the back.
- You two,
... keep an eye on the window, but keep
out of sight. I don't want any casualties.
Two on the road. The rest, you got the front of the house.
Keep close to the wall. The rest follow me.
- You think he's gonna shoot us?
- Would you?
You'll find a pastor in school.
Cut him loose and calm him till I come.
He'll be rather annoyed. Stay here.
Captain Hardt, this is Commander
Blacklock, of the Royal Navy.
If you throw your gun out the window
and surrender, you'll be treated as a POW.
Otherwise, you'll be shot.
- Nobody at school, sir.
- What?
Untie the poor devil!
Cast off!
- Hold on. A passenger's coming.
- Aye, sir.
Mr. Harris, commander Blacklock asked
for you. I'll tell him that you caught the boat.
I asked myself: if all is as it should be,
Why I am prevented from seeing Rev. Harris?
I can tell you: Harris was tied in school
because he was a nuisance.
You were lucky not to suffer the same fate.
- Under Blacklock you would have.
- I cannot pretend to understand.
I'll help you. And attempt was made
by German spies to kill Anne Burnett
and put an agent in her place.
Fortunately, it failed.
They drop her off a cliff, but by a 100
to 1 chance a patrol boat fished her out.
She said enough so we grabbed the spy in Thurso.
Then we had the idea of replacing
her with a counter-spy.
In short notice we found a brave volunteer,
the girl you know as Anne Burnett.
The Anne Burnett at school is not the teacher,
Nor the Anne Burnett the Germans intended.
- She's not Miss Burnett at all.
- Substantially correct.
- Then who is she?
- That's an official secret.
- What's the matter, Blacklock?
- Hardt, sir, he got away.
- The German?
- Locked Harris, and he wears his clothes.
Excuse me, sir.
Signals? Send a call to all patrols in the island.
He won't get away, sir. He can't do any harm.
All aboard for mainland!
Stop!
All, in single file.
One by one. Look.
Put them aboard there.
Here we are, sir. All present.
- Eight German prisoners.
- Look starved to me.
Are they off a U-boat?
It blew. On one of their own mines.
One of their...?
- You think they'll see the joke?
- Guess not.
Here, by the right!
You're the right man!
I do not understand.
It's like talking to stuffed dummies.
Well, stand easy; you're depressing.
- What do I do with them?
- Split them up. Forr'ard and aft.
Steward!
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Give them some coffee.
Poor devils.
- Walter!
- Well, James?
I am not superstitious, but I do not like this.
Mind the engines and I'll mind the ship.
No mind my mentioning.
Six weeks I've been trying to fix
a new lining to the bottom of this.
I do not like those Germans. Bad luck.
They could go in the St. Ninian with the other prisoners.
They were crowded. They will not give us problems.
4 in the forecastle and 4 in the saloon,
a sentry for four. No one can reach them.
Well... Maybe.
Too young.
- Father, they only speak German.
- Shut up or die.
Captain Hardt. Taking command of the ship.
Take care of the crew. Come on!
Your replacement, he's overdue.
No sausages. It's what you eat, right?
- The Germans!
- Stop!
Below there!
Doddie!
Give me the rocket launcher.
- Get off my bridge whoever you are!
- Drop that pistol.
- You're my prisoner.
- Get out of here or I'll shoot!
Do not move.
- Your ship is in my hands.
- And who might you be?
- I'm a German officer.
- On those clothes?
They do for the present. Where is your wireless kept?
- There is none.
- No wireless?
No German went out of the house
while I was at duty, Admiral.
I handed over to the patrol; there
were nine of them and one of me.
You didn't suspect that passenger on the pier?
Where were your eyes, man?
He jumped aboard when she was casting off.
I did deliver your message, commander.
- Yes, you told us that before.
- That will do, Bob.
- You got to give credit to Hardt ...
- I give to him for causing this infernal cheek!
He can't get away, sir.
Signals: Wire Scrabster and Thurso.
"Arrest German officer masquerading as a passenger. Stop".
To all the patrols.
"Order St. Magnus to heave to and
await destroyer." Repeat that back.
Go below! Go!
Attention.
- I need two men.
- Very well.
Keep an eye on the crew and passengers.
To monitor crew and passengers! Come with me.
Stay calm. Let's take a look.
Out.
- How did you escape?
- That I must thank you for.
Sentiment made you stop being Fraulein Thiel
- Or Miss Burnett...
- Mrs. Blacklock!
That's one secret you kept well. How considerate.
Now you captured the ship what will you do?
Lay a course for the submarines at Sandwick.
- You can't do that!
- I'm not under your orders!
- But it is full of mines!
- We shall both take our chance.
- This doesn't mean you and me.
- Right: It means the life of hundreds of my comrades!
- But the children and women here aren't people?
- That will be at your door, not mine.
The war broke. You forget, as I did before.
- You are English, I'm German. We are enemies!
- I like that better.
And I. It simplifies everything!
Come on.
- Lay a course, East.
- East, captain.
Now what, sir?
Listen. You're held as prisoners of war.
I do not want any noise and panic.
Whoever disobeys orders will be shot.
With one exception.
- Be quiet!
- Easy.
A19, A24, A7... St. Magnus spotted
by 3 patrols. Still on the right course.
There are eight German prisoners on that ship.
- What are you doing, you can go home.
- Thank you.
If they join forces with a desperate man like Hardt...
- Message from A17.
- No sighting. She's overdue.
She set a different course between A7 and A17.
Sandwick Bay.
My wife is on that ship.
- Orderly.
- Yes, sir.
I want to see the commander of the flotilla.
I'm sorry. You'll have to forget personal affairs.
Sir?
We believe St. Magnus was captured by German
prisoners who are making a rush for Sandwick.
Cmdr Blacklock will advise you on the course to be taken.
Go out to Switha Sound and cut her off.
- She's to be sunk?
- If they won't surrender...
Skipper!
- Are you there, Walter?
- Huh?
We can't keep at this speed much longer.
It's murdering my bearings.
Fearful pressure on engines.
I don't know how the ship'll put up with.
- Where are we going?
- Due east.
Soon we will leave the patrolled area.
- We're in the hands of the providence.
- No we are not; we are in the hands
of a man who cares nothing for his life or yours.
It's all my fault, cause I forgot that we were at war,
that the war kills any decent human feeling.
- Can you shake it up a bit?
- No, it's flat out now.
The old man is deaf or dumb.
Or is a U-boat he's after.
Out.
Out!
Funny; there's no sign of the old tub yet.
- Perhaps they altered course again.
- Not likely.
Have a look, Felix.
Is not the St. Magnus?
It's her all right. What's she doing so off course?
- Looks suspicious.
- What a cinch!
We gotta save all the torpedoes!
Nothing in the orders to stop
us sending a couple of shells...
Stand by to surface!
Guns trough, action stations.
Objective: steamship. Steer right.
Remove the British flag.
The U29!
Schuster! Schuster!
Do not shoot! Do not shoot!
It's me, Hardt!
There's someone semaphoring from the bridge!
H - A - R
There's firing down the haven.
Better take a look. Hold the course, Number One.
Wear the lifevests. Get to the lifeboats.
Stay calm.
To the lifeboat!
Keep calm and put on the floats.
Donald, stop what you're doing
and come up to the deck. Hurry up.
There she is!
Stand by. Guns out.
- Don't fire!. She's sinking by the stern.
- They're taking to the boats, sir.
Captain, look, destroyer!
Crash dive!
She's being shelled by a U-boat.
We'll have a crack at it, Number One!
Objective: submarine.
Depth charge... ready!
- You may leave.
- Not without you.
That's an order!
It's time to go, miss. Take it to the boat, James.
It's my old ship that sank us.
Come on now Missi, come on. Hurry.
What are you doing here?
You should get into a boat.
If you don't mind, I'd rather stay.
Suit yourself. It's your business.
Captain, have you got a cigarette?
Never smoke them, but got
a pipe if you want it.
- Never smoke a pipe.
- A little late to learn.
She's there. I can see her!